[Music]
[音乐]
there's a reason no one makes videos
没人像我一样做视频是有原因的，
like me because no one wants to live the
因为没人想过
life I live or be in my head they they
我这样的生活，也没人想了解我的想法，他们会很
would be miserable are you
痛苦的。你
happy
快乐吗？
um I I'm going to be honest so far more
嗯，说实话，到目前为止，不快乐多于
unhappy than happy well has it ever
快乐。你有没有想过彻底
crossed your mind to quit YouTube as a
退出YouTube？
whole oh yeah of course really yeah are
哦，当然想过。真的吗？哦，
boy Mr Beast Mr Beast Mr Beast he is the
天哪，Mr Beast，Mr Beast，Mr Beast，他是
biggest YouTuber on the planet and he's
地球上最大的YouTube博主，他正在
building Empires I mean is there
建立自己的帝国。我的意思是，还有
anything this man can't do your business
什么是他做不到的吗？你的
Empire is much bigger than most people
帝国比大多数人
realize yeah I mean I'm only 26 and we
想象的要大得多。是的，我的意思是，我才26岁，我们就
have the largest YouTube channel in the
拥有世界上最大的YouTube频道，
world and Beast games is going to
Beast Games将会
shatter some pretty crazy records and we
打破一些非常疯狂的记录，我们赚了
do nine figures and feasts but a lot of
九位数，还有各种盛宴。但这很大程度上
that stems from being a very confused
源于我小时候很迷茫，格格不入，
child that's not fitting in that feels
感觉自己
like a freak plus I really wanted to
像个怪胎。另外，我真的很想
take care of my mom because when I was
照顾我妈妈，因为我
11 we literally went bankrupt and lost
11岁的时候，我们家真的破产了，失去了
everything luckily it worked out and
一切。幸运的是，后来一切都好起来了。而且，
it's because I'm really good at
这都是因为我真的很擅长
obsessing over one thing more than
沉迷于…… 比
anyone else on the planet like us 10
地球上任何人都更关注的一件事，比如我们投入1000
millions of dollars zombies games but
万美元制作僵尸游戏，就是尽全力把第一
it's about making season one as good as
季做到最好。
possible and I just really love solving
我真的很喜欢解决
complex problems like how many kids do
复杂的问题，比如
you think are in child labor in West
你觉得西非有多少童工？
Africa just on Coco Farms it's 1.5
光是Coco Farms就有150
million and so with febles we were
万。所以，我们和Febles合作，
trying to get over a million kids out of
试图让超过100万的儿童摆脱
child labor but the ironic part is the
童工的困境。但讽刺的是，
more I help people the more I get like
我帮助的人越多，收到的负面信息就越多。
I've read over 5,000 messages telling me
我已经读过5000多条让我自杀的信息。当然，
times where I would cry but if my mental
有时候我也会哭，但如果我的心理
health was a party I wouldn't be as
健康状况像一场派对，我就不会像现在这样
successful as I am this is the price you
成功。这就是你
have to pay but when is enough enough
必须付出的代价。但什么时候才算够呢？说实话，
this has always blown my mind a little
这件事一直让我有点震惊：
bit 53% of you that listen to the show
53%的听众
regularly haven't yet subscribed to the
还没有订阅我们的
show so could I ask you for a favor
节目。所以，在我们开始之前，我能请你们帮个忙吗？
before we start if you like the show and
如果你喜欢我们的节目，
you like what we do here and you want to
喜欢我们在这里所做的一切，并且想要
support us the free simple way that you
支持我们，最简单的方法
can do just that is by hitting the
就是点击“
Subscribe button and my commitment to
订阅”按钮。我承诺……
you is if you do that then I'll do
如果你这样做，
everything in my power me and my team to
我和我的团队将竭尽全力
make sure that this show is better for
确保这档节目
you every single week we'll listen to
每周都能为你带来更好的体验。我们会认真听取
your feedback we'll find the guest that
你的反馈，找到
you want me to speak to and we'll
你想让我采访的嘉宾，并
continue to do what we do thank you so
继续做好我们一直在做的事情。非常感谢！
[Music]
[音乐]
Jimmy we've really just only met and you
吉米，我们才刚认识，但你对我来说就像一个
are already to me a bit of a Rubik's
魔方，
Cube okay in so many ways and I've been
在很多方面都是如此。我一直在
trying to piece the pieces together to
努力拼凑这些碎片，去
understand the the uniqueness of you
理解你的独特之处，
because you're so unbelievably unique we
因为你真的非常独特。我们
just drove over here in the car and
开车过来，
hearing you speak about the way that you
听你谈论你的
view life and speaking to you yesterday
人生观，昨天也和你通了
on the phone I've I've interviewed
电话。我采访过
hundreds and hundreds of people and I've
成百上千的人，但我从未
never ever met someone who has the
遇到过像你这样对人生有独特见解的人。
you are truly
你真的很
unique what do I need to understand
特别。我需要了解
about your earliest years to understand
你早年的哪些经历才能真正了解
who you are oh boy um yeah my earliest
你呢？哦，天哪。嗯，是的，我的早年经历……
I I'm just stubborn man I just never
我这个人很固执，我从不放弃。
give up I mean there was there's no
我的意思是，
world where I ever would have quit I
我根本不可能放弃。 我就是，我的
just I I mean we're just jumping right
意思是，我们直接进入正题，
into it it's a great no intro or
没有介绍
anything just boom this how you hold
什么的，直接就开门见山了。这就是我跟
people um when I was 11 I just said I'm
人相处的方式。嗯，我11岁的时候就说过，我要
going to be a YouTuber I'm going to die
成为一名YouTuber，我要为此奋斗到死，
trying and I meant it and there was like
我是认真的。
even if no one still watches my videos
就算到现在没人看我的视频，
to this day I would still be going um
我也会继续做下去。
and so people hate it but I'm just the
所以有些人讨厌我，但我就是
most competitive stubborn person you'll
你见过的最有竞争心、最固执的人，我从不
ever meet and I just never give up where
放弃。说
honest it honestly it feels like it was
实话，我也不知道这从何而来，感觉就像刻在
just in my DNA and my bloodstream my Mom
我的DNA里，流淌在我的血液里一样。我妈很
hated it growing up we'd always argue
讨厌我这样，我们总是吵架。
and like you know she has this thing
你知道，她有种魔力，一旦
where like once Jimmy sets his mind to
Jimmy下定决心要做
something he just never stops and it
某件事，就绝不会停下来，这
would always piss her off CU when it was
总是让她很生气。比如，当她
YouTube and she wanted me to be studying
想让我学习
or things like that but I really don't
或者做其他事情的时候，她就更生气了。但我真的不
know it's it's just always been how I am
知道，我就是这样。
and I think a lot of people have these
我觉得很多人都有这种
weird Tendencies and they tend to like
奇怪的倾向，他们往往会
try to like uh unlearn them and like I
试图改掉这些倾向。 我
had phases in my life where I was like
人生中有些阶段会想，
am I too extreme like people are very
我是不是太极端了？别人都觉得我很
intimidated by me because I just am so
吓人，因为我太
obsessed with work and I'm so Allin and
痴迷工作了，我全身心投入。我会
like is this like unhealthy should I try
想，这样是不是不健康？我应该试着
to be more like a normal human
更像个正常人吗？
especially when I was a teenager it's a
尤其是在我十几岁的时候，这
lot easier it's funny when when you're
很容易做到。有趣的是，当你
making lots of money it's like admirable
赚了很多钱的时候，你会觉得很了不起，很值得
it's respectable it's like look those
尊敬，你会觉得，看，这些都是
are traits we want but when you're not
我们想要的品质。但如果你
successful you know you're a lunatic
不成功，拥有这些品质的人就会被当成疯子。所以那时候
back then I'd occasionally be like man
我偶尔会想，
like should I try to be more normal but
我应该试着更正常一点吗？但
I just could never do it anytime I tried
我就是做不到。每次尝试，
was in Middle School like all you do is
我都做不到。我以前也说过，有一件事我印象特别深刻，就像刻在我脑海里一样。有一次，一个高中生在我上初中的时候跟我说，你
talk about YouTube like do like know how
除了YouTube什么都不会，你还会别的吗？
to do anything else like like you're
你
just like a freak and I tried to like
简直是个怪胎。我试着
watch South Park you know cuz that's
…… 你知道，《南方公园》吧，因为
what a lot of people in my school watch
我学校里很多人都看这个来
to fit in and I just couldn't I was like
融入群体，但我就是不行。我觉得
this is such a waste of time I don't
这太浪费时间了，
like I could be working right now and I
我本来可以去工作。我
tried to do all these things to like fit
尝试做各种事情来融入群体，
in and I eventually just like stopped
但最终我干脆不
talking because I just didn't relate to
说话了，因为我跟谁都合不来。
anyone and um people used to call me
嗯，以前有人叫我
mute like one of my teachers literally
哑巴，我有个老师甚至直接
asked like if I was mute like cuz that's
问我是不是哑巴，
how little I spoke because no one in the
因为我说话真的很少。
school I went to was entrepreneurial or
我上的学校里没人有创业精神，也没人会去
one to build businesses and I just
创业，我就是
didn't want to do anything else and um
不想做别的。
yeah eventually I started to succeed
嗯，后来我开始成功了，
found other lunatics and now life's
找到了其他志同道合的伙伴，现在生活
great but you know I like to tell the
很棒。你知道，我喜欢
story when I'm on podcast because if you
在播客里讲这个故事，因为如果你
have a younger viewer who's in that same
有个年轻的听众也处在同样的
spot you're not the problem it's your
境地，那问题不在于你，而在于你的
environment and you just got to put
环境，你只需要让
yourself in a better environment what
自己置身于一个更好的环境。
about your parents mom and dad you talk
你的父母呢？你经常
about your mother a lot yeah um no I I
提到你妈妈。嗯，不，我没有，
don't I didn't get it from them what
我不是从他们那里遗传的。
what influence did they both have on you
他们对你有什么影响？ 嗯，关于
um well I don't really talk about my dad
我爸，我不太常提起他，
much that's you know a long story don't
你知道，那是个很长的故事，就不
need to get into it but my mom
细说了。至于我妈，说
honestly it was it wasn't it's great now
实话，以前可不是这样。现在
me and my mom have a phenomenal
我和我妈
relationship but on the come up it was
关系很好，但以前很
it was pretty rough because in 2008 they
艰难。2008年，他们
were over leverag so we literally went
过度举债，我们家
bankrupt and so they they you know had
破产了。他们之前有一些
properties that they used to get other
房产，用来买其他
properties and then when everything
房产，结果经济
collapsed they lost basically everything
崩溃，他们几乎失去了一切。
and so my mom was working two jobs and
我妈当时打两份工，勉强维持生计。
you know barely getting by and so we
所以
like I I didn't see her that much
我很少见到她，
because when I I was coming home from
因为我放学回家的时候，
school she was doing her second job so
她还在忙第二份工作。
it was a lot because she was a single
她是个单亲
mom raising us she's working all the
妈妈，要养活我们，她一直都在工作。
time you know um my I don't talk about a
嗯，我不太常说这些。
lot of this you know I have Crohn's
我患有克罗恩
disease so I was very sick growing up my
病，所以小时候身体很不好，我
brother also had issues as well and so
弟弟也有健康问题，所以
in our teenage year she's just trying to
我们青少年时期身体都不太好。她只是努力维持生计，
get by and take care of us and then you
照顾我们。
know she comes home and she just has
她回家后，发现有个
this brat that's being annoying and like
小屁孩特别烦人，比如
I want to be a YouTuber and she's just
我想当油管博主，她就一直
begging me sometimes she would literally
求我，有时候甚至
cry and beg me to do homework and I mean
哭着求我做作业。我当时真的，真的，我不是故意要惹她生气，
mean it in a mean way but I mean I even
但有一次
one time I literally told her if you
我真的跟她说，如果你那么
want my my homework done so bad why
想让我做作业，那
don't you just do it you know like
你自己不做吗？我当时就是这么跟
that's that's what I told my mom like
我妈说的，我到底在干什么？
what am I doing I don't know like I was
我也不知道，我就是不在乎，我只想
just want to be successful I want to
成功，想
build businesses and so it was like
创业。所以，她真是个可怜的孩子，幸好我成功了。
now I spoiled her she's great she has
现在我把她宠坏了，她很棒，她有
her second home anything she could ever
自己的第二个家，她想要的一切她都有。
one she has and so the first uh thing I
所以，我做的第一件事就是
did was take you know start paying my
开始给
mom take care of her once I started
妈妈钱，在我开始赚钱之后照顾她，
making money cuz she gave everything to
因为她为了让我有今天的成就付出了一切，如果没有她，
like get me where I am and I wouldn't be
我不可能走到
where I am now but it was like it was
今天。但感觉
like me and her spoke different
我和她之间就像是说着不同的
languages when I was younger you know
语言一样。 你知道，
she she didn't want me to end up like
她年纪小的时候，不想让我落得和
them you know and you get screwed and uh
他们一样的下场，你知道，被坑，
not have much money and like the path I
没多少钱，我当时
was going down was just basically like
走的路基本上就是，
oh I'm going to be a homeless drug
哦，我要成为一个无家可归的
addict and like her brain couldn't
瘾君子。她无法
compute the world I saw and my brain
理解我所看到的世界，我也无法理解
couldn't compute the world she saw and
她所看到的世界，我们之间一直
it was constant friction who was looking
摩擦不断。谁来
after you then if she was busy working
照顾你？如果她忙于工作，
and you were at home and your dad's not
你待在家里，而你爸爸又不在
around who takes care of you uh I just
身边，谁来照顾你？嗯，只有
me and my brother we're just there I was
我和我哥哥，我们就在那里。我当时就在
just making videos you making videos
做视频。你也在做视频，你
what age did that start the videos I
几岁开始做视频的？我
started at 11 11 yeah so I I I'm 26 now
11岁就开始了。是的，我现在26岁了，
I can't really remember life before
我不太记得YouTube之前的生活了，
YouTube like my earliest memories are
我最早的记忆
basically when I started making videos
基本上就是我开始做视频的时候。
you said earlier um you don't talk about
你之前说过，你很少谈起
your dad much yeah
你爸爸。是的，
you don't have to talk tell me about it
你不必谈。跟我说说吧，
but why don't you talk about the your
但你为什么不经常谈起你
father much ah don't worry about it I
爸爸呢？啊，别担心，我
know your mom has spoken about him
知道你妈妈以前谈过他。是的，那有点……
tumultuous relationship yeah exactly
关系确实不太好，没错，
they didn't have the best relationship I
他们的关系确实不太好。我的
mean that's a topic for another day
意思是，这又是另一个话题了，说实话，以这种不太
honestly kind of a sour way to start it
愉快的方式开头有点不好。不过，
off but yeah it's my mom is great I love
我妈妈很棒，我爱
back at it she was perfectly reasonable
她。她以前会哭着求我做作业，很多事情她都会哭。当我们开始赚钱的时候，她会因为我不肯存钱而哭，她觉得风险太大了。我的意思是，她说的那些话其实都很有道理，对吧？现在回想起来，她当时的做法完全合情合理。
in what she was doing I'm just a
我只是个
deranged lunatic and was way too
疯子，一心想着
obsessed with building the business and
发展事业，太执着于此了。
way too Allin um like it's very cute one
嗯，有
time she like when we had I don't
一次，我们好像是
remember like some month or made like
某个月赚了
100 grand and I'm like okay perfect now
10万美元，我当时想，太好了，
I can spend 100 Grand this next month on
下个月我可以把这10万美元花在
videos and she like took like 5,000 of
视频上了。结果她偷偷拿出5000美元，瞒着
it and put it away for me in my own bank
我存到了我自己的银行
account without telling me but in case
账户里。万一
you know I ever went you know was
我以后……你知道的……
overleveraged or went bankrupt like they
就像他们那样过度负债或者破产，
did and um I found out about it and uh
然后我发现了这件事，
she's like please don't take this money
她就说：“求你了，别拿走这笔钱，
just let me set aside anything stop
让我留点钱，别把
spending everything on videos and I was
所有钱都花在视频上了。” 我当时想：“
like no this is perfect now I can spend
不，这太好了，现在我可以花
more like this is awesome thank you Mom
更多钱了，太棒了，谢谢妈妈！”
and like but to me I don't I don't
但对我来说，我真的不
really feel risk like I if anything it
觉得冒险有什么问题，如果非要说的话，冒险反而让
like Risk excites me and like I have
我兴奋，而且我对风险的承受能力
very high threshold for it um so yeah we
很高。所以，我们之间真的
just we literally weren't communicating
沟通不畅，
the same language but I don't remember
我不记得当时我多大了，
what age it was but eventually after I
但最终，在我承担了
took enough risks and figured it out my
足够多的风险并弄明白之后，我
mom just said to me you know what I'm
妈妈对我说：“你知道吗，我要
going to trust you like I have faith and
相信你，我相信你。” 从那以后
everything got so much better after that
一切都好多了，
point when like she stopped staying up
她不再
all night worrying about me and worrying
整夜担心我，担心
whether or not I was making the right
我做的
decision when she's just like Jimmy I
决定是否正确，而是对我说：“吉米，我
trust you I know this you think about
相信你，我知道你
this all day like I'm going to just
整天都在想这件事，我会
follow your lead and our relationship
听你的。” 从那以后，我们的关系就一直
has been you know perfect ever since
很好。
then if IID asked 10-year-old Jimmy how
如果IID问10岁的吉米：“你现在怎么样？”
are you doing what would what would he
你当时在做什么？他会
have said uh 10 I don't know but if you
说什么？呃，10岁？我不知道。但如果你在我
asked me at like 12 or 13 I probably
12、13岁的时候问我，我可能会说“
would have been like [__] like no one
操，没人看
watches my videos I just really want to
我的视频，我就是想当个
be a YouTuber I um I gotta I gotta make
YouTuber，我得，我得把这
work why did you want to really be a
事做成”。你为什么这么想当
YouTuber because kids say that but the
YouTuber？因为小孩子都会这么说，但
extent to which you said it and the
你当时那么认真地谈论这件事，并且那么
focus that you had on that particular
专注于
goal of being a YouTuber CU there's many
成为YouTuber这个目标，这很不可思议。
things you could have focused on you
你可以专注于很多事情，比如当个
could have been a video game player
游戏玩家什么的，
whatever whatever but YouTube is a
但YouTube很特别，
particularly interesting thing because
因为
you're on camera people are seeing it
你在镜头前，有人在看，而且有
there's a metric which decides how
指标来衡量
successful you are um was there any
你的成功。嗯，
element of the on camera part that
镜头前的那些事，有没有哪些因素
was helping to solve for like the
帮助你缓解了当时
feeling of isolation that you you seem
你似乎感受到的那种孤独感？
to have at that time no Community yeah I
没有社区。是的，我
think it's more to do with just I I
觉得更多的是因为……
found out that when I was at a young age
我小时候，
probably around 11 that there YouTubers
大概11岁左右，发现有些YouTuber
dollars a year and I was just like oh
一年能赚几十万美元，我当时就想，哦，原来如此。 当然是为了
that's it like just the money yeah of
钱，
course because back back then we didn't
因为那时候我们
have money and I really wanted to take
没钱，我真的很想
care of my mom and and just my family in
照顾我妈妈，也想照顾我的家人。
general so it was like everything it was
所以，一切都像是为了钱，这就是
like this is what I love doing I I've
我热爱的事情。我从来没有像现在这样享受过其他事情。
I do this plus I could see a path where
而且，我能看到一条路，
I could actually retire my mom take care
我可以让我妈妈退休，照顾
of her pay her back for you know all the
她，补偿她那些
night she worked so long so we could
辛苦工作的夜晚，这样我们就能过上
um live comfortably and things like that
舒适的生活等等。
so it's just kind of the thing is I've
所以，有
one thing that irks me is when people
一件事让我很恼火，那就是人们
try to like put someone's motivation
试图把别人的动机简单地
into like one little bucket like we're
归类。我们是
very complex creatures and like you know
非常复杂的生物，比如，
you have a girlfriend I I I would never
你有个女朋友，我永远不会
say oh you just like her because she's
说“哦，你喜欢她只是因为她
pretty but you like her because she's
漂亮”，但你喜欢她，是因为她
pretty but you probably also like her
漂亮，但你可能也喜欢她，
because she's smart you probably also
因为她聪明，
like her because you know she's fun to
她可能也很有趣，
be around she likes similar shows blah
她喜欢类似的节目等等。
blah you probably if we sat here for 10
如果我们坐在这里10个
hours you could probably give me a
小时，你大概能给我
thousand reasons why you like your
一千个你喜欢你
girlfriend so it's like it's very
女朋友的理由。所以，
annoying when people try to put why you
当人们试图把你
like doing a certain job or building a
喜欢做某份工作或创办
certain business into one bucket oh you
某项事业的原因简单地归结为“哦，你
just do it because of money what if I do
只是为了钱才这么做”时，真的很烦人。但如果我做这件事是
it because I like money and I enjoy it
因为我喜欢钱，享受赚钱的过程，而且这是
and it's a way to do this and it's a way
一种实现目标的方式，也是一种
to communicate with people and community
与人、与社区沟通的方式，
and these other things you know what I
等等，你明白我的
mean and I think that's a common flaw we
意思吗？我认为这是我们常犯的错误，事情并
try to do it's like it's not that simple
没有那么简单。
I think it's a lot of people can't
很多人无法
understand someone being so relentlessly
理解一个人为何能如此执着地
focused on something with the level of
专注于某件事，并
that you've shown yeah and so and I
展现出你这样的投入和持续的奉献精神。是的，所以，我
don't know how I I agree because it's
不知道该怎么形容我的想法，因为这
very weird like how like I have extreme
很奇怪，就像我有一种极端的
Obsession to the point where like I just
痴迷，以至于我对某件事的
think about stuff the same like for me
思考方式总是千篇一律。对我来说，连续
something 16 hours a day for seven days
七天每天思考16个小时比不断
shift constantly I'm like really good at
转换思路要容易得多。我非常擅长
just obsessing over one thing more than
专注于一件事，比
anyone else on the planet i' if I were
地球上任何人都更甚。如果
to say what's my superpower it's that I
要说我的超能力是什么，那就是……
something and I can just have the same
我会对某件事无休止地痴迷，同样的
thoughts over and over and over and over
念头会一遍又一遍地重复，
again it's it's very weird like it's it
这很奇怪。
for me grinding YouTube for those 10
对我来说，在YouTube上苦苦钻研了
years or whatever where no one was
十年（或者更久），根本没人看，这根本不像是工作，这就像是我的一部分。这肯定是一种
been a deep Obsession because you were
深深的痴迷，因为你
doing it when no one was really watching
做这些的时候根本没人看，没人
or paying attention or really when the
关注，
platform was there was literally a day
平台也还没普及。
when I was uh 19 or 20 where I got I
我记得有一天，大概19、20岁的时候，我
woke up joined a Skype call with my
醒来后和朋友们开了个Skype电话，我们当时在分析
engineering you know why certain videos
为什么有些视频会火。
do well or whatever and I remember that
我记得那次
call being over 18 hours long and then I
通话持续了18个小时，然后我
hung up went to bed woke back up the
挂断电话去睡觉，
next day and instantly got back like
第二天醒来又立刻接通
call and pick back like that was the
电话，就这样，
level of like hours we were putting in I
我们投入的时间简直惊人。我的
mean I didn't know anything besides just
意思是，除了努力让视频火起来，我什么都不懂。
anything else that you showed that level
你当时还有其他表现出这种程度的
of obsession too so at that age no from
痴迷吗？在那个年纪，没有。
I would say from 11 to well 11 to 15 it
11岁到15岁的时候，我的生活
was a mix of YouTube and baseball but
是YouTube和棒球的混合体。但
when I turned 15 I got Crohn's and I
15岁的时候我得了克罗恩病，体重
went from like 190 pounds down to 139 I
从190磅降到了139磅，
lost all muscle I had and so I was like
肌肉全没了。所以我就想，
all right I'm not playing baseball in
好吧，大学棒球是没戏了。然后我就想，算了，干脆把
it it's just all in on uh YouTube and um
所有精力都投入到YouTube上吧。
and then up until really febles it was
直到最近几年，我的生活
basically just YouTube for whatever I
基本上就是YouTube。我
never thought I would find like this
从没想过自己会对
kind of love for build like I thought it
健身这么感兴趣，我以前以为健身就是
was specifically video making but I have
做视频，但
found over like the last two or three
过去两三年里，我发现
years just in general I just enjoy
我真的很享受
entrepreneurship and I've been really
创业的过程，而且我特别喜欢
Feasta and other things and so which was
Feasta之类的东西，简直到了痴迷的程度。这
very weird like when I first started a
很奇怪，我一开始创办
chocolate company it was like kind of a
巧克力公司只是个
side thing but the more I started to
副业，但随着我
work on it I got a lot of the same high
投入的越多，我获得的快感和
as I got when I was making videos just
做视频时一样，只是
in different ways and so now I'm like I
方式不同。所以现在我觉得我对
know way too much about the chocolate
巧克力行业了解得太多了，
industry I'm like it's pretty crazy I
简直不可思议。 我
never imagined I would have put the
从没想过我会投入
thousands of hours I've poured into
数千小时来
building feals and so I think just in
构建框架，所以
general it's just I just really love
总的来说，我真的很喜欢
solving consistent complex hard problems
解决持续不断的复杂难题，这大概就是我每天
bed and like the harder the problems the
起床的动力吧。而且问题越难，我就越兴奋。
problems I want to talk about that and
我一直想谈谈这个，
also Feast tables but you mentioned
还有盛宴表。你刚才提到了
Crohn's disease there and a lot of
克罗恩病，很多
people don't know what that is and the
人不知道这是什么，也不知道
impact it has on someone's life are you
它会对人的生活造成什么影响。你
aware of it I am because I had a team
了解吗？我了解，因为我的团队
member that had it so um in order to
成员中有人患有这种病。为了在
they had to leave and stuff like that I
他们不得不离开的时候给予支持，我逐渐
got a little bit more aware of what it
了解了这种病的含义
means and what how it impacts you but
以及它对人的影响。
could you give me your perspective on
你能谈谈你的看法吗？好的。
that yeah so Cron's disease words is
克罗恩病，简单来说就是
when your immune system attacks itself
免疫系统攻击自身。
so uh yeah when I was 15 I just started
嗯，我15岁的时候，开始一天
going to the bathroom 8 nine 10 times a
跑八九十趟厕所，
day not digesting any food because my GI
什么食物都消化不了，因为我的消化系统好像在
track is like literally just attacking
攻击
itself it's very weird your immune
自己。这很奇怪，你
system in your gut thinks your gut is a
肠道里的免疫系统会误以为你的肠道在攻击自己。 它就像
foreign Invader and so it just starts
外来入侵者，所以它就开始
attacking itself which if you're just
攻击自身。如果你
using the bathroom 10 times a day not
一天跑十趟厕所，
digesting food it's why you drop weight
食物又消化不良，这就是为什么你会迅速掉体重，
rapidly and it hurts like crazy because
而且会痛得要命，因为
it gets very inflamed and it feels like
它会严重发炎，感觉就像
someone's stabbing you in the gut with
有人用刀子不停地捅你的肚子一样。
really bad which is what I had so I lost
我的情况就是这样，所以我瘦了
50 pounds which is crazy because I was
50磅，这太疯狂了，因为我本来就
already relatively lanky um and we were
比较瘦。我们
just trying different medicine and then
尝试了各种不同的药物，
eventually I'm on a pretty extreme
最后我用了一种
medicine called Remicade where just
叫做类克（Remicade）的强效药物，它
basically you n your immune system which
基本上会抑制你的免疫系统。这就是
is why my voice sounds a little off
为什么我现在的声音听起来有点怪怪的。
right now CU I just got the flu I got
我刚得了流感，得了
covid six times I got shingles like I
六次新冠，还得了带状疱疹，我总是
get sick all the time because for me to
生病。因为我的消化系统要
have my GI track stop attacking itself
停止攻击自身，
we basically have to shut down my immune
基本上就得抑制我的免疫系统，
immune system so I just get sick all the
所以我的免疫系统非常弱，总是生病，就像
time like why I have like random rashes
我身上会莫名其妙地出现皮疹之类的。
pretty pretty brutal to be honest and
说实话，这真的非常痛苦，而且
then it randomly flares up sometimes and
它还会随机发作。 有时候会突然醒过来，感觉特别
just makes you very sick very tired like
难受，特别累，
honest like if someone like if you wake
老实说，我的生活就像是硬核模式。如果有人
up and you have energy like you're
醒来就精力充沛，那他们就已经比我强太多了。
like I you know it's it's makes things
你知道，这让事情变得
way more difficult and so you still wake
更加艰难。当然，
up with some days where you don't have
有些日子你醒来后仍然会感觉
energy of course which is really hard to
精疲力竭，这
believe for someone who's so productive
对于一个在外人看来如此高效的人来说，真的很难相信。是的，
for everybody looking on yeah it's you
你必须
just got to really love what you do I
真正热爱你的工作，
mean and push through it it's uh it's
并且坚持下去。这
pretty brutal because then you compound
很残酷，因为你还要不断
that with always being sick and I mean
生病。比如，
yeah like I just spent four days in a
我刚在南非的医院住了四天，
hospital in South Africa cuz I got the
因为我得了
flu and it just takes me a lot longer to
流感。我
recover from certain things so um it's
从某些疾病中恢复过来需要更长的时间，所以，这很
brutal and that's where like if I didn't
残酷。如果我不那么
work so much I would spend more time
忙，我会花更多时间
researching Crohn's because surely
研究克罗恩病，因为肯定有
just destroying my immune system and
比破坏免疫系统更好的方法来阻止它。
ideally I don't do that deep into my 30s
理想情况下，我不想在30多岁
and 40s so I see it as a little bit of a
甚至40多岁的时候还这么做。 我觉得这有点像
Band-Aid but um you know I've met with
权宜之计，但是，你知道，我已经和
the top Crohn's doctors in the world and
世界上顶尖的克罗恩病专家会面了，
so far they're like this is just the
到目前为止，他们都认为这就是
answer and you're just lucky your you
解决之道。 你只是运气好，你
know gut isn't attacking yourself um
知道，你的肠胃没有攻击自己。嗯，
so but I don't know I I feel like the
但是我不知道，我觉得他们给
medicine they give people Crohn's is
克罗恩病患者开的药
kind of silly and there's got to be a
有点傻，肯定有
better way to treat it I mean the
更好的治疗方法。我的意思是，
ultimate solution is they just cut me
最终的解决方案就是把我
open and cut out a large part of my GI
切开，切除我大部分的消化道，
track and then there you go but you know
然后就完事了。但是你知道，
it's I observed in the the team member
我观察到我团队里有一位患有
that I had that had Crohn's just a bit
克罗恩病的成员，他的
of a mental roller coaster as well
精神状态也像坐过山车一样起伏不定，
because there's an certain
因为这种病具有一定的
unpredictability to it exactly which
不可预测性，这
makes life oh it's even worse when
让生活变得很糟糕。哦，当
you're filming because you got this huge
你在拍摄的时候情况就更糟了，因为你身处一个价值数
multi-million dollar set and 200 people
百万美元的庞大片场，有200个人
waiting on you and you know sometimes
等着你，你知道，有时候
you don't know if you're going to have a
你不知道自己会不会
flare but you just got to go [__] it and
发作，但你只能硬着头皮，喝点
just down some caffeine and crank it out
咖啡，然后继续拍下去。
I got diagnosed with ADHD you did yeah I
我被诊断出患有注意力缺陷多动障碍（ADHD）。是的，我被诊断出
got diagnosed with ADHD and it made me
患有ADHD，这让我开始
think a lot about myself and the way
思考自己，思考我的为人。
that I am it's not NE I'm not the type
我不是神经质，我不是……
think it really means much I am just who
我不是那种会把某个标签当回事，或者觉得它意义重大的人。我就是我。
I am have you um are you in any way
你……你是不是
neurod Divergent uh I've been told Yeah
神经发育迟缓或者有分歧？嗯，有人跟我说过，是的，
by Dr I ADHD I mean I'm not surprised
医生说我有注意力缺陷多动障碍（ADHD）。我的意思是，我并不惊讶，
because I just sit and obsess over
因为我总是会坐下来，不停地钻研各种
things constantly but I think um I'm I'm
事情。但我认为……我对
happy with however my brain is wired I
我的大脑构造很满意，我
don't really care to change it um I I
并不想改变它。嗯，就像我
mentioned earlier you you like solving
刚才说的，我认为我最大的超能力之一就是我的执着。有些人可能会觉得这是个弱点，但我觉得，如果你思考解决问题的次数是其他人的三倍，你肯定会想出不同的解决方案。你之前也提到过，你喜欢
hard problems consistently when you
持续解决难题。回想过去
think back over the last 10 years of
十年，
your life and the the success you've had
你成功
solving some of these hard problems if
解决过一些难题，如果
you were to like break it down into some
你要把这些成功分解成几个
components of um that you've learned one
组成部分，你学到的其中之一就是
of them is Obsession that you've said
执着。你说过，是的，
others I
其他的是什么？我的
mean it's all the typical stuff like you
意思是，都是些典型的特质，比如……
are obviously who you surround yourself
显然，你身边的人很重要。
with and um luckily I just got around
幸运的是，我
the right people in my later teenage
在青少年后期遇到了对的人，
years because I I feed off the energy of
因为我会受到
the people probably around me it's so
周围人的影响，这很
obvious like I start to talk like them I
明显。比如，我会开始模仿他们的说话方式，对
become interested in the things they're
他们感兴趣的事情感兴趣。
interested in I mean this is all obvious
这些都是显而易见的
stuff I'm sure you've heard of billion
道理，我相信你肯定听过无数遍了。
times so but you know just got to I
但是，我
always have to be protective of the
必须保护我
people I'm around because whatever they
身边的人，因为他们
say is what I started thinking on and
说的话会成为我思考的焦点，
that's what I started obsessing over and
我会开始痴迷于此。
you know um one of the best things that
你知道，
happened with febles is I just reached
Febles 的成功之处在于，我联系了
out to all the fastest growing chocolate
所有发展最快的巧克力
companies all the fastest growing snack
公司、零食
businesses and everything and just
公司等等，并
became friends with a lot of the
与很多创始人成为了朋友。
founders and you know that's what would
你知道，这
have probably taken me eight nine years
可能需要我八九年的时间
to like solve you know after 18 months
才能解决的问题，在 18 个月后，我
you know was probably one of the top 10
可能已经跻身
people in the world when it comes to
全球
running a chocolate company and
巧克力公司运营领域前十名，并且对巧克力有着
understanding deeply just because it's
深刻的理解。这
just ch codes um what about detail
不仅仅是巧克力代码的问题，还有细节问题，以及对
sweating the small
小事的关注。
stuff one of the things that I saw I was
我在
reading the this that handbook that was
阅读时发现…… 就是那本
laked on the internet and one of the
在网上流传的手册，
things I saw throughout that was this
我读的时候发现，里面充斥着
real obsession with the 1% and the small
对那1%的精英和各种小事的执着。顺便问一下，
stuff how do you feel about this by the
你对此有什么看法？还有，
uh with with some of my employees when I
我
was probably
大概
22 so there are some things that I'm
22岁的时候，和一些员工一起写了这些东西。所以，有些内容我
like I read I'm like oh wow I was an
读了之后会想，哇，我当时真是个
idiot but for the most part most of it
傻瓜。但大部分内容
still stands the tested
仍然经得起考验。
um and I I do think it's very helpful
而且，我觉得它很有帮助。
you know what's funny a lot of CEOs have
你知道吗，有趣的是，很多CEO都
actually told me that they make their
告诉我，他们会让
employees read this um went around all
员工读这本书。这本书在
of our slack channels we we all read it
我们所有的Slack频道里都传开了，我们都读了。
yeah which is funny because I'm like
这挺有意思的，因为我当时就想，
damn I should make an updated version of
我应该写个更新版，让
it so everyone uh but yeah the thing is
每个人都读一读。这本书
it's the the core Crux of it is like
的核心是“
extreme ownership and don't make excuses
极端所有权”，不要找借口。
and you know um people always yeah I
你知道，人们总是……嗯，我的
mean the damn I'm getting a lot of DJ Vu
意思是，我写这本书的时候经常会想起DJ Vu，那时候的时代背景和现在不
a different time back then too because I
一样，因为我当时……
I was 21 22 and I just found that I was
我完全不知道我21、22岁的时候在干什么，我发现自己一直在
constantly telling like teaching the
重复同样的话，一遍又一遍地
same or teaching people the same things
教别人同样的东西，
over and over again and it was always
总是强调要承担全部责任，要勇于
accountability like sure I guess it was
担当。当然，我猜有些事情可能
out of your control but it could have
超出你的控制范围，但
been in your control if you just thought
如果你多思考一下，
through it more if you just really cared
如果你真的在乎，一切就都能掌控了。这就是
and that's what I was just trying to
我想
convey in it and the other thing that
表达的。还有一点，从
your work is just this idea something
你所有的作品中都能感受到，
that I've learned from you just from
我
speaking to on the phone yesterday that
昨天跟你通电话时就学到了这一点：没有什么
nothing is impossible yeah exactly and
是不可能的。没错，
watching Beast games over the last
过去几周我一直在看Beast Games的比赛，也
couple of weeks but also speaking to
跟
some of your team there's clearly this
你的团队成员聊过，很明显，
through line with everything that you do
你所做的一切都贯穿着一种
of like extreme what it appears to me to
极致的——在我看来是
be extreme ambition MH and it doesn't
极致的雄心壮志。MH，你觉得这并非像我理解的那样是
appear to be extreme ambition to you in
极致的雄心壮志。我的
extreme ambition to me yeah I mean it's
意思是，如果
just I mean is does physics allow it
物理定律允许，
then yes it's possible it just is it do
那么是的，这是可能的。问题是，
we want to put the time in I mean it's I
我们是否愿意投入时间。我的意思是，我
I feel like people over complicate a lot
觉得 就像人们总是把很多事情复杂化一样，
of things um and something you've
嗯，有些事情是你经过
trained over time or have you always
长时间训练才做到的，还是你一直都这么
thought that I think I've just H it's a
认为？我觉得我只是……嗯，这是个
good question I've never I don't know
好问题。我从来没有……我不知道
why but when people tell me I can't do
为什么，但当人们告诉我我做不到某件事时，
something I and I don't know where this
我不知道这种感觉从何而来，反而
came from it makes me just want to do it
会让我更想去做。说
more to be honest if you tell me I
实话，如果你告诉我我
shouldn't do something that's fine but
不应该做某件事，那没关系；但
if you tell me I can't then I just
如果你告诉我我做不到，我
everything in my body just wants to go
浑身上下都想说“去
[__] you I obviously can I just I don't
你的”，我明明可以，我只是不
know if I should but I can and then I I
知道我该不该做，但我可以。然后，我
don't know it's like the the the thing
不知道，关键是，要想爆
is like to go viral you have to do
红，你必须做
something that's never been done before
一些前所未有的事情。
I've told this story before of like you
我以前讲过这个故事，你
know if you're driving down the road and
知道，如果你开车在路上，
you see a cow who cares it's a [__]
看到一头牛，谁会在意呢，它就是一
cow but if you're driving down the road
头牛而已。但如果你开车在路上，
and you see a purple cow you're like
看到一头紫色的牛，你就会想，
you've never seen that before and it's
你以前从来没见过这种牛，这是
something you weren't expecting you're
你意想不到的，你会惊呼“我的
going to go holy [__] and you're going
天哪！” 然后你会去跟
to go tell your friends about it you're
朋友们说这件事，你会
going to remember that you'll probably
记住这件事，你可能
even think about it randomly once every
每隔几年还会突然想起它，比如“这他妈怎么会有一头
purple cow and it's like it's the same
紫色的牛？”。这就像同一
thing just one was a little purple and
件事，只不过其中一头是紫色的。
like you can apply that same like uh
你可以把这个
analogy to ideas like when you're
比喻应用到其他想法上，比如你在
scrolling through social media to find a
社交媒体上浏览
video to watch there's things that you
视频时，有些东西你
know have been done before you've seen
知道以前有人做过，你以前看过，
it's you know roughly similar to stuff
你知道，它和以前的东西大致相似，
before you're just going to scrore pass
你只会扫过去，以后再也
it you'll never think about it again
不会想起它，
just like you'll never think about a
就像你永远不会想起
[__] cow on the side of the road and
路边那头该死的牛一样。
then there are ideas that are like the
然后还有一些想法就像“
purple cow idea which is what I try to
紫牛”那样，这也是我努力
do which are things that make you go
想做的，就是那些让你觉得“卧槽，我从来没见过这个”的东西，让你觉得“我必须点
I I have to click this or I'm not going
开看看，不然
to be able to sleep tonight because like
今晚睡不着觉了”，因为你会想“
why is this video no way they did this
这视频怎么可能？他们怎么能做得这么好？”。
right but those typically are very hard
但通常来说，这种想法很难实现，
and usually to get that purple cow
通常要达到“紫牛”
effect they've never been done before
效应，就必须创作出以前从未有人做过的东西，创作出前所未有的东西。
and something's never been done before
以前
there's usually a reason because it's
通常都是有原因的，因为这真的
very [__] hard so you just kind of
非常难，所以你
have to train yourself to like not
必须训练自己不要
resent very difficult complex hard
怨恨那些非常困难、复杂、棘手、
original problems and actually run
原创的问题，而是要
towards them because those are the ones
迎难而上，因为
that you know tend to have more of the
你知道，这些问题往往更容易产生“
Purple Cow effect where people have to
紫牛效应”，人们会
watch it and viewership is very
去看，而且观看量会呈
exponential it's way easier to get 50
指数级增长。
million views on one video than it is to
一个视频获得5000万的观看量比
get a million views on 50 videos right
50个视频获得100万的观看量容易得多，对吧？
and so um and because it like kind of
所以，嗯，因为它呈
goes exponentially and it's like you
指数级增长，就像你
know pretty winter take all in the top
知道的，那些热门
videos like you just really have to lean
视频几乎包揽一切，你真的需要
into that purple cow effect if that
利用“紫牛效应”。如果这说得通的话，那就
makes sense makes perfect sense if you
完全说得通了。假设我们要编写
coming up with a new how to succeed in
一本关于如何在
Mr BEAST's production handbook now what
Mr. BEAST的制作手册中取得成功的新指南，那么
would be the the the top five if I was
最重要的五点是什么？如果我
applying for a job with you what five
申请你的工作，
characteristics would I need to
我需要
demonstrate to be successful you got to
展现哪五项特质才能成功？你必须
be very coachable because whatever I
非常乐于接受指导，因为我
teach you today is going to change you
今天教你的任何东西，
know a year or two from now always
一两年后都会改变。不断
learning always improving coachable um a
学习，不断进步，乐于接受指导，嗯，这很重要。
big thing for me is you got to see the
我的意思是，你得真正看到
value in working here like you really I
在这里工作的价值。
just I don't this isn't like a a job
这不仅仅是一份工作，
this is a career like if you don't you
这是一份事业。如果你看不到
you're working for me in 10 years then
十年后你还会为我效力的前景，那我就很难像
into you at the level I want like I'm
我希望的那样在你身上投入资源。
not I don't like training someone for
我不喜欢培训一个人
six months they work here for a year and
六个月，他们在这里工作一年，
then I lose them what I like is I train
然后我就失去他们。我喜欢的是，我培训一个人
someone for a year and then I get nine
一年，然后在接下来的九年里获得丰厚的
years of dividends on the back end where
回报，
they Crush at their job and I'm
他们在工作中表现出色，而我
constantly paying them more because
不断地给他们涨工资，因为
they're becoming more valuable at time
他们的价值也在不断提升。这
like that is like the eighth wonder of
就像世界第八大奇迹——
the world is investing heavily in an
对一名员工进行大量投资，
employee and then they stick around for
然后他们能为我效力
a decade you know what I mean it's like
十年。你明白我的意思吗？
there are some of my top guys that I
我的一些顶尖人才，我
spent three or four years in the
花了三四年时间与他们一起
trenches with training and working with
训练和工作，比如
you know they're like Tyler who writes a
泰勒，他为我写了
lot of my videos and directs them I you
很多视频剧本，也执导了很多视频。你
know probably talk to him five six hours
知道，我可能每天都和他聊五六个小时，持续了
four years and now because I can't spend
四年左右。 现在，因为我没时间陪他，
a you he spends 100% of his time writing
他把100%的时间都花在写
the videos directing the videos obsessed
剧本、导演视频上，他简直痴迷于此。
over that whereas I could theoretically
而我理论上只能
Max spend five % of my time so he's
花5%的时间，所以他自然会在
going to naturally just [__] on me on it
这方面瞧不起我，
because he can spend way more time on it
因为他能投入更多的时间。
and it's like so you know I have full
你知道，我
faith in him but the dividends that I
对他充满信心，但这么多年来，我
pouring all that time and effort into
投入了那么多时间和精力在
him and now he knows exactly how I think
他身上，他给我的回报却微乎其微。现在他完全了解我的想法和
what I value that I don't even really
价值观，以至于我有时甚至不用
have to communicate with them sometimes
跟他沟通，只要去
I can just show up to film and like I
拍摄就行了，我
just trust that it's good you know and I
完全相信他做得好。
have a bunch of people across all my
我的所有公司里都有很多像他这样的人，这太棒了。
great and if you know in a world where
如果你知道，如果
Tyler's still working here 10 years from
Tyler十年后还在这里工作，那么他这样的
someone like that is UN fathomable it is
人的价值简直无法估量，对一个企业来说，这
quite literally the eighth wonder of the
简直就是世界第八大奇迹。这就是
that's what I want but you only get
我想要的，但你只能找到
those kinds of people they see the value
那些真正懂得自身价值的人。
for you know working for you and so they
为你工作，所以他们
have to like deeply believe like the
必须深信，
more valuable I become to this company
我对公司越有价值，得到的
the more I'll be rewarded and they like
回报就越多。他们必须真心
actually want to dedicate their life to
想为公司奉献一生，这一点
the business so that's very important
非常重要。
because if I really don't get that Vibe
因为如果我真的感受不到这种氛围，
then it's not fair to both of us because
对我们双方都不公平，
I'm not going to invest in you like I
我不会像应该的那样投资你，因为我
should because I don't think you're
觉得你
going to be here in 10 years and then
10年后可能就不在这里了，到时候
you're going to feel that and it creates
你就会明白这一点。所以，嗯，
so uh coachable uh sees the value you um
可塑性强，能看到你的价值，嗯，
obviously obsessed I I don't I just
显然很执着。我不
don't like working with mediocre people
喜欢和平庸的人一起工作，我真的
I I mean I really just can't stand it
无法忍受。
depressed um is if I have to work with
如果我必须和
someone who's just not Allin and just
一个不全力以赴、不
loves what they do um it's just a lot of
热爱自己工作的人一起工作，那会让我最快感到沮丧。嗯，就是很多类似的事情，我
you know stuff like that that I'm sure
相信
if you listen to like a Steve Jobs
如果你听听史蒂夫·乔布斯的
interview or something that he talks
采访或者他谈到的东西，就会发现这些都是
about it's just the the typical traits
典型的特质：执着、可塑性强、全心投入。
obsessed coachable Allin sees the value
看到了价值，
and what is the single worst
而最糟糕的特质是什么？
traits mediocrity I mean it's it's just
平庸。我的意思是，
like cuz they're not bad enough where
他们不够糟糕到需要被
you fire them but not good the problem
解雇，但也不够优秀。问题在于，
is like I mean and you see it in full
你会发现，
effect great people just love working
优秀的人喜欢和
with great people they do and there's
优秀的人一起工作，这是真的。和优秀的
people that pulls some kind of animal
人在一起，会激发你内心深处的某种潜能，
out of you that just makes you want to
让你想要
do more and push more and believe things
做得更多、更努力，甚至相信有些事情
aren't possible and I don't know when
是不可能完成的。我不知道，当我和
you put me around a bunch of other
一群
successful entrepreneurs I just turned
成功的企业家在一起时，我就像变了
into a different human than if you put
一个人；而如果我和
me around I don't know a bunch of people
一群我认识的、
who are just running small businesses
只是经营小本生意、对工作漠不关心、也没有什么
have much ambition I'm like two
抱负的人在一起，我就像
completely different humans and you see
完全不同的两个人。你会看到
that same thing in full effect you put a
同样的道理：你把
bunch of a players around more a players
一群顶尖人才放在一起，
they just build off of each other but
他们会互相促进，共同进步；但如果
you like put two or three C players
你把两三个平庸之辈放在
amongst a bunch of great people and
一群优秀的人中间，
they'll start pulling them down they'll
他们就会开始拖累其他人，
start making them not want to work as
让他们不想工作，
much and make work not as fun and so
让工作变得不再有趣。所以
everyone knows get rid of the C players
大家都知道，要把平庸之辈赶走。 很明显，玩家们会
right obviously get rid of people who
淘汰那些
aren't all in blah blah blah it's the
不够投入的人，比如那些
ones that are like they're not an a
既不是A级
player but they're not a c player so
球员也不是C级球员的人。
it's kind of hard because you still feed
这有点难，因为你仍然会受到他们的
off the energy and if you get enough of
影响，如果这种人太多，就会
them it just drags the overall culture
拖垮整个团队的文化。
down so those are like the worst um I
所以这些人是最糟糕的。我的
mean not everyone can be these like
意思是，不是每个人都能成为那种
world-ending Monsters you know there are
能改变世界的怪物。你知道，有
a lot of mundane things like you I mean
很多琐碎的事情，比如你，我是说
the book controller and accounting I
账务主管和会计。我的
mean probably doesn't have to be the
意思是，他们可能不需要是
best in the world but you know when it
世界上最好的，但是你知道，在那些
comes to like the mission critical
关键任务上，
things like making videos and things
比如制作视频之类的，
like that like just the great people got
优秀的人才必须被
to be surrounded like that's one of your
围绕着。
number one jobs as Leaders just to make
作为领导者，你的首要任务之一就是
sure your great people are working with
确保你的优秀人才与
other great people because that's like
其他优秀的人才一起工作，因为
people leave jobs isn't money you know
人们离职的首要原因不是钱，你知道
what I mean it's that's like number four
我的意思吗？钱大概排
on the list don't ask me to listen all I
在第四位。别问我所有细节，我
don't remember I just know the number
记不清了，我只知道最重要的一点是他们是否
one thing is do they enjoy who they're
喜欢自己。 和同事
working with and people will leave their
一起工作，人们会
job because they hate working with
因为讨厌和同事一起工作而离职，远比因为
because of money have you ever been
薪水而离职要早得多。你有没有因为
frustrated that the people you've hired
雇佣的人达不到
don't match your level of obsession no
你的期望而感到沮丧？没有，
because I just find the people that do
因为我总是能找到符合你期望的人。真的有人符合吗？
are there people that do oh yeah I've
哦，当然有。
there's so many people in my uh business
我的公司里有很多这样的人。我的
um I mean obviously you have to take
意思是，你当然要
care of them pay them well like they're
照顾他们，给他们优厚的待遇，因为
they're not the kind of people that'll
他们不是那种只拿
just make the standard rate but um yeah
标准工资的人。
like people like kitner Russ and you
比如像基特纳·拉斯这样的人，
know even people on our editing team I
还有我们剪辑团队的人，
mean they're putting in most week same
他们每周的工作时间
hour same amount of hours as me and
跟我一样多，而且
they're all in see the vision it's like
他们都理解我的愿景。找到
it's hard to find those kinds of people
这样的人很难，
but um you know when you do you got to
但是，你知道，当你找到他们的时候，你必须
treasure them and recognize that they're
珍惜他们，意识到他们是
unicorns and you have almost 500 roughly
稀世珍宝。我们公司有将近500人，大概
500 people uh probably uh I think the
500人左右，
production company were around 300
制作公司大概有300人，
feasts around 100 and then probably
Feasts公司大概有100人，然后可能还有
another 40 50 scattered months
40人左右。  50个月零零散散的日子，其他一切都乱糟糟的。
everything else most Founders that I
我跟大多数创始人
speak to describe scaling headcounts as
聊过，他们都把扩大员工规模描述为
job more people more problems right yeah
工作中最糟糕的部分——人越多问题越多，对吧？嗯，这我完全
that's uh that's an understandment yep
理解。尤其
especially as someone like you who's a
像你这样，
creative at heart and who is very
内心充满创意，又非常
focused and obsessed on I guess the show
专注，甚至痴迷于节目
and producing as you say often the I I
和制作的人，就像你说的，我经常
want to produce the best videos we
想制作出我们能做到的最好的视频。
possibly can of course and then all this
当然，随之而来的是各种各样的
other [__] comes with it which is like
其他破事，比如
HR which every founder I speak to hates
人力资源，我跟每个创始人聊过，他们都讨厌人力资源。
I mean yeah I the the worst part is I
我的意思是，最糟糕的是，我
just have this very once in a um I just
只有这么一次
very rare opportunity where I have so
难得的机会，能获得如此
much attention and so many people watch
多的关注，这么多人观看
my content and and I wish I had I just
我的内容。我真希望自己
wish I had more experience building
有更多创业经验。
businesses you know I'm only 26 and this
你知道，我才26岁，这
is my first real business of every every
是我的第一个真正意义上的创业项目。
employee Milestone we hit it's my first
我们达到的每一个员工里程碑都是我第一次
time hitting that right like when I hit
达到，对吧？比如，
100 employes that was my first time
员工人数达到100人的时候，那是我第一次达到这个数字。而这次，也是
getting there and this that this was my
我
first time going from 100 to 200 200 300
第一次从100人增长到200人。  300，
and like with what I know now I could
以我现在的了解，我当然可以
have done it so much faster obviously
做得更快。
and it's just you know it's a little
你知道，这有点
brutal because like you like scaling
残酷，因为
febles from you know 0 to 100 was way
从零到一百发展壮大Febles
easier than doing my production company
比创办我的制作公司容易得多，
because I had been through the ringer
因为我
before and I learned a bunch and I get
之前经历过很多磨难，学到了很多东西，而且
better with time and I it's just the mo
随着时间的推移，我的能力也在不断提高。说
honestly the most annoying part is just
实话，最令人恼火的是
ignorance right like because a lot of
无知，对吧？因为我犯的很多
things mistakes I make I look back and
错误，回头看的时候，我会想，
I'm like oh yeah I probably should have
哦，是的，我可能应该早点
brought in people with more experience
引进
working at a larger company earlier here
在大公司工作过、更有经验的人，
I waited a little too long here I
我当时等得太久了，我应该早点这么做。
probably should and it's just like
这真的很
brutal because if I had known these
残酷，因为如果我早知道
things i' would be way further along but
这些，我现在会走得更远。但
I mean that's just how you learn just
我的意思是，这就是学习的方式，你必须
got to make 10,000 mistakes every
犯一万个错误，每个
founder says the same founder I've spoke
创始人都会这么说，我跟很多创始人聊过，他们都这么
to says the same that unknown unknowns
说，那些不知名的人也不
exactly know it's just like so that's
知道。所以，
where I mean my big thing recently has
我最近一直在
just been trying to find people who have
努力寻找那些
successfully skilled businesses and like
成功经营过企业的人，
bring them into my organization and
把他们招进我的团队。 我要向
learn from them because I'm just so
他们学习，因为我真的
tired of like being like [__] I should
厌倦了总是后悔自己当初没做得更好，
have known better but I didn't because
因为
I've never done this before and so I'm
我以前没做过这件事。所以我正在
trying to find a lot of great people who
努力寻找很多有经验的人，让
have been through it so they can like
他们
kind of Mentor me along the way so I
一路指导我，这样我就能
make less mistakes which has been really
少犯错，这真的
good um we brought in a new SE Suite
很有帮助。我们最近引入了一套新的软件工程套件。这始终是一个
recently um I it's like always a hard
很难
balance because I try not to in the past
平衡的问题，因为我过去总是试图避免这种情况。你
I I have like you know decisions are
知道，我的决策就像
kind of like pendulums and I have a uh a
钟摆一样，我有个
problem where I like I'll identify
问题，就是我会发现
something and I'll overcorrect the
一些问题，然后过度纠正
pendulum one way and I'm like h no I
钟摆的方向，之后我就会想，哎呀，我
should have just stopped in the middle
应该在中间就停下来。我
and like my overcorrection in the past
过去的过度纠正表现为，
was like corporate people try to build
企业人士试图建立
too many systems and they kill
太多的系统，扼杀了
Innovation and so I was very anti likee
创新。所以我非常反对那些拥有
people with too much corporate
太多企业
experience because they're going to just
经验的人，因为他们会
destroy all the creativity but you know
扼杀所有的创造力。但你知道，这就是
that's why we're making so many
为什么我们会犯这么多
organizational fuckups because we don't
组织上的错误，因为我们没有
have anyone who's actually built the
真正建立过
business at this size and so you know
如此规模业务的人。 所以你知道，
the pendulum was on the right and I
钟摆原本在右边，我把
swung it all the way to the left of no
它摆到了完全不搞
corporate and now I think we're in the
企业化的最左边，现在我认为我们处于一个
healthy medium where you know obviously
健康的中间状态。当然，
the people on our SE suite and the
我们软件工程师团队的成员和
leaders should have lots of experience
领导者应该在
managing people at this size and skill
管理这种规模和技能的团队方面拥有丰富的经验，
but it's just finding the right people
但关键在于找到合适的人，他们
who can do it and build systems in a way
能够胜任这项工作，并以一种
where it doesn't Crush creativity and
不会扼杀创造力的方式构建系统，而且
they actually value the product over
他们真正重视产品而不是
ease the D and my I'm on the a TV show
简化流程。我参加了
called Dragon de in the UK and um my
英国一个叫做《龙之谷》的电视节目，嗯，我的
stuff is significantly smaller it's like
节目规模要小得多，大概只占
a percentage of your your viewership but
观众的一小部分，但
even I am slightly terrified with hiring
即使是我，在招聘
people because it's quite clear to me
员工时也有些害怕，因为我很清楚，
that there's a huge incentive for anyone
任何与我共事的人都有很大的动机
that I work with to say that I did
说我做错了什么。
something bad and in the early days of
在
my first business um what happens is the
我创办第一家公司的早期，
journalists go to everyone that works
记者会采访公司里的每一个人，
there yep and they ask them what was he
问他们“你怎么样？”。
like you you have the same problem you
你也面临着同样的问题，
have the same conundrum where anyone has
同样的困境，每个人都有动机
an incentive that works for you when
对你有利，因为
they leave so many different incentives
他们留下了太多不同的动机
to throw an arrow at you on the way out
来攻击你。 真是让人无语，
the door how how do you contend with
你怎么应对
this yeah I mean you hit it on the head
这种情况？嗯，你说的太对了。
uh you know I have four or 500 people
你知道，我现在有四五百人，
right now but we've also worked with
但我们
thousands of people in the past and so I
过去也和成千上万的人一起工作过，所以我
think it's just what comes with it but
觉得这是不可避免的。但
at the end of the day you know as long
归根结底，只要
as what we're doing is moral and ethical
我们做的事情合乎道德和伦理，就像
like like you said they're going to
你说的，他们就会
throw arrows but you know I I'm just a
攻击我们。但你知道，我只是个
problem solver it's like whenever I see
问题解决者。每当我看到那些攻击，
the metaphorical Arrow I just go you
我就会想，
know what's the problem and if we did
问题出在哪里？如果我们做错了什么，该如何
something wrong how do we fix it or if
弥补？或者，如果
it's not an actual problem it's just
这不是真正的问题，只是
rumors I mean it is what it is and so
谣言，那又怎样？这就是现实。所以，
yeah I think it just comes with part of
我觉得这是不可避免的。
it um I mean it sucks and it's
嗯，这很糟糕，也很
unfortunate but you also to think like
不幸，但你也要想想，
most people don't like their jobs too
大多数人也不喜欢自己的工作，
and so it's not like this is even
所以…… 这甚至
specific to our industry like you know
在我们这个行业里也很常见。你知道，
just go ask a 100 random Americans of of
随便问问100个美国人，在
all the jobs that worked in their life
他们做过的所有工作中，有
how many did they deeply enjoy and do
多少是他们真正喜欢并且乐在其中的？
would they have nothing negative to say
他们是不是都没什么负面评价？
so I think it's just part of it you know
所以我觉得这只是其中的一部分，你知道，
U it's almost like a Pastime for a lot
对很多
of people just to like trash talk their
人来说，吐槽
old jobs or whatever um has any of that
以前的工作之类的几乎成了一种消遣。嗯，这些批评有没有影响
stuff ever got to you any criticism
到你？是的，批评总是会影响到我。
but I mean the thing is independent of
但我的意思是，撇开
that kind of stuff it's just like I mean
这些不谈，
for we are averaging like 200 million
我们平均每个
views a video like you know like uh most
视频的观看量是2亿，你知道，大部分都是
of it unique viewers like we're talking
独立观众，我们说的是全球
like two plus percent um sometimes 3% of
2%以上，有时甚至3%的
humans alive watch every piece of
人类会观看
content I put out you know depending on
我发布的每一条内容，这取决于
how well the Channel's doing and so like
频道的表现。所以这
that means like you could I could upload
意味着，我上传
a video and then with uh 365 days days
一个视频，365天后，
later you could grab 33 random humans
你可以在地球上随机找到33个人观看，
anywhere on the planet especially
尤其
because we do doves you know what's even
因为我们做的是鸽子题材。更
crazier is there you know YouTube's not
疯狂的是…… 你知道，YouTube
in China so that's like two to three% of
在中国没有用户，所以除了中国以外，大概只有 2% 到 3% 的
humans alive excluding China um or
人口在使用。嗯，或者说，
China's mixed in there but if you just
中国用户也算在内，但如果只算除
take people excluding China it' be more
中国以外的人口，大概是
like 3 to 4% um but you could just grab
3% 到 4%。嗯，你随便
33 random people on the planet and one
在地球上找 33 个人，
of them on average would have seen that
平均下来，他们中至少有一个人看过这个
video because the views are so [__]
视频，因为它的播放量实在太高了。
high so yeah I mean there's a lot of
所以，是的，我受到了很多
criticism that's thrown at me and the
批评。
thing is you since stuff so Global
问题是，有些东西是全球性的，
sometimes you know transcends culture
你知道，它有时会超越文化，
and not everyone views everything and so
但不是每个人都会看所有视频，所以
everyone has different opinions and
每个人都有不同的观点
stuff like that which is why it will
等等。这就是为什么
drive you crazy at our scale if you try
在我们这种规模下，如果你想让所有人都满意，你会抓狂。
to make people happy because even if 99%
因为即使 99% 的
of people are deeply happy which is an
人都非常满意——这已经是一个
insane hit rate like if you make a piece
惊人的成功率了，比如你制作了一个
of content 99% of people that watch it
内容，99% 的观众都
love it that is wild which that kind of
喜欢它，这很不可思议，这种
stuff doesn't happen but in our case if
情况几乎不可能发生。但在我们这里，即使
just 1% unhappy that's 2 million people
只有 1% 的人不满意，那就是 200 万人，这
which is more than anyone else even gets
比其他任何人的
on video views on videos so which will
视频播放量都多，所以
feel like an insurmountable amount of
感觉就像…… 铺天盖地的
criticism and feedback and it's very
批评和反馈，很
easy to like trick your mind into
容易让人产生一种错觉，
thinking damn everyone hates me because
觉得“天哪，所有人都讨厌我”，因为
you're just you know focus on the 1%
你只关注那1%的人，而不是
instead of the 99 so I just came to the
99%的人。所以我最终
point where you know I just have to have
意识到，我必须建立
my own internal guidelines of like do I
自己的内在准则，比如，
think what I'm doing is good do what I
我做的这件事是否合理？是否符合
think you know is moral ethical do do I
道德伦理？我是否
believe in what I'm doing if so [__] it
相信自己所做的事情？如果是，那就随它去吧。
like I'm never going to be able to make
我永远不可能让
everyone happy so I and if you just you
每个人都满意。如果你
let the whims of the internet kind of
让互联网的喜好来
decide what is okay and what's
决定什么是可以接受的，什么是不可以
acceptable and and when you're being bad
接受的，那么无论你做得好
or good then you you you don't have a
还是坏，你都会失去原则，没有脊梁，没有立场，
stand for nothing and and it it will
这会
just destroy you mentally um and so I
摧毁你的精神。
mean I don't know what age I was when I
我不知道自己是什么时候开始有这种
kind of got in that mindset but I just
想法的，但我当时就想，
was like I'm going to decide and I'm not
我要自己做决定，我不能让
going to let the internet decide you
互联网来决定
know what is okay and what's not and
什么是可以接受的，什么是不可以接受的。从那以后，
then ever since I got to that point you
我就一直坚持这样做。
know people criticize me for something
人们批评我，
and I'm like I don't agree then I have
我就说我不同意，然后我很容易就想，
like it's easy for me to just go oh well
哦，好吧，
I don't agree not going to make everyone
我不同意，不可能让每个人都
happy I believe what I'm doing is right
满意，但我相信我做的是对的，然后就继续
and um just move on the brain isn't
前进。大脑本来就
isn't designed for for this though no
不是用来处理这些的，真的
it's not this is what I've come to learn
不是，这是我逐渐明白的。
so do the podcast it goes well I'm it
所以，做播客的时候，
feels like at the start everyone loves
感觉一开始每个人都喜欢
me yeah and then I get further down the
我，是的，然后随着时间推移，
line and it feels like everyone [__]
感觉每个人都他妈的
Hates Me y because they you get attacked
恨我，因为你会受到攻击，
from you can never do anything right
你永远都做不好任何事。
especially I've probably read mes like
尤其是我可能读过很多
comments or tweets or I've probably in
评论或推文，或者我这
my lifetime read over 5,000 messages or
辈子可能读过超过5000条信息或
comments or something telling me to kill
评论，让我去死，
myself you know what I mean you know
你知道我的意思吗？你知道，到底是什么驱使
just like and what would possess someone
一个人留言让
to tell you to like leave a comment
你
where it's like [__] kill yourself
去死，
you know what I mean so agreed like
你知道我的意思吗？所以，同意，
you're we were not meant to receive this
我们本来就不应该收到来自
anywhere in the world you know what I
世界各地任何人的这种反馈，你知道我的
mean just all con you know consistently
意思吗？ 你知道，
day in and day out for for my in my case
日复一日，持续了十多年，对我来说，
now over a decade has it ever really got
这真的让
to you oh yeah of course I mean it it
你感到压力吗？哦，当然，我的意思是，它一直都让你感到压力，
does all the time or it used to all the
或者说曾经一直都让你感到压力。
time I like I said what does that mean
就像我说的，这实际上意味着什么？
in reality if I'm a fly on a wall in one
如果我像一只苍蝇一样，在
of those moments where you can recall it
你回忆起那些
really getting to you I mean back in the
真正让你感到压力的时刻，你会怎么想？我的意思是，以前，
day but I wasn't as confident in my
我对自己的
ability to to be successful and you know
成功能力没有那么自信。你知道，
when you're probably 20 and you're
当你大概20岁的时候，你
hiring all these people you're you know
雇佣了这么多人，你知道，
I I have highrisk tolerance but I'm
我风险承受能力很高，但我把赚到的
reinvesting every dollar I make I I'm
每一分钱都再投资了。
you know I'm hiring my friends from
你知道，我雇佣了我的朋友，
school I hired my mom like these people
雇佣了我的妈妈，这些
I really care about are depending on me
我真正关心的人都依赖着我。
and then you know I upload a video and
然后，你知道，我上传了一个视频，结果很
it does bad and then people you know I
糟糕。然后人们知道，我
pour all my time and effort into it but
投入了所有的时间和精力，但
you know maybe it doesn't come across as
你知道，它可能不像
well like the V and you know some people
V那样受欢迎，你知道，有些人
might have interpreted as lazy and you
可能会认为你很懒。你会
read a comment being like wow what a
看到一条评论说，哇，真是个
[__] lazy like I thought you made
懒鬼，就像“我以为你做的
great videos or this this video sucked
视频很棒”或者“这个视频很棒”。 糟透了，
and and you read that and the video is
你读到那些评论，视频播放量也不理想，然后
underperforming and you're like [__]
你就会想，操，是不是
maybe I am being too Reckless and you
我太鲁莽了？你
know I mean there's definitely times
知道，我的意思是，
where I would cry you know just because
我肯定会哭的，因为
I would just be like [__] am I like not
我会想，操，是不是我
doing this right or like they don't
做错了？是不是他们不
understand I put a lot of time into this
理解我投入了那么多时间？
or or whatever why why you sometimes
或者其他什么原因？有时候
you're like [__] does the algorithm them
你会想，操，是不是算法
hate me am I being suppressed or
讨厌我？是不是我被压制了？或者
whatever back in the day um when was the
其他什么原因？以前，嗯，上次有这种
last time that happened that feeling
感觉是什么时候？嗯，
of um yeah Pro there was like a a month
Pro，
probably last year where I I felt a
大概去年有一个月，我有点
little bit of that just because um you
这种感觉，因为，你
know just sometimes occasionally the
知道，有时候，
rumor and drama Mill gets mun up but you
谣言和八卦会突然冒出来，但你
just got to snap out of it and like I
必须振作起来，就像我
said just go do I believe in what I'm
说的，继续做下去。我相信我正在
doing do I it's like it's hard because
做的事情吗？这很难，因为
you know anytime I do anything good it's
你知道，每当我做了什么好事，
you know people are always like uh they
人们总是会说，呃，他们
try to we're we're like condition in
试图……我们……
America now when someone does something
现在在美国，当有人做了好事时，总会有
good there's always some alterative
其他
motive and I've I've always been
动机。我一直…… 我一直很
straightforward and just said a world
坦诚，就说一个
where I help people is just better than
我能帮助别人的世界比一个
a world where I don't like I don't try
我不喜欢的世界要好。我不想编造什么
to come up with this crazy like story of
疯狂的故事，比如
was younger and now I I just want to
小时候有人帮助过我，现在我只想
give back and cry I'm just like yeah I
回报社会，然后哭着说，是啊，我
can make viral videos and I think a
可以制作爆款视频，我觉得一个我能制作
world where I do viral videos that help
帮助别人的爆款视频的世界比我不喜欢的世界
people are better when I don't you know
要好。你知道，这就是
just kind of that's my answer um but it
我的答案。但是，
always does suck when people try to just
当人们试图……
like I don't know the it's funny the
我不知道，这很讽刺。
more good you do the more people think
你做的好事越多，人们就越觉得
you're secretly evil and it's like why
你暗地里是个坏人。就好像，为什么
can't I just help people because it's
我不能只是因为帮助别人很有趣而帮助别人呢？
fun you know so occasionally those will
你知道吗？所以，有时候这些话会让我很难过，我就想说，
get to me and I'll just be like guys you
你们根本
don't even know me like and like you
不了解我。
would think sometimes you'd read like
有时候，你们会在网上看到一些关于
when I build wells in Africa or help
我在非洲建水井、帮助
blind people see or things like that you
盲人重见光明之类的报道，
you would think I'm Hitler I mean it's
你们会觉得我是希特勒。我的意思是，
crazy like how people portray it and I
人们描述我的方式太疯狂了。我
just I don't know I wish people just
只是……我不知道，我希望…… 人们只是
understand like in my opinion a world
理解，在我看来，一个
where I help people is just more fun
我帮助别人的世界
than a world where I don't and it's
比一个我不帮助别人的世界更有趣，这
really not that deep the people around
其实没那么复杂。你周围的人会怎么想？那些
the drama and that kind of stuff impact
纷争之类的会怎么影响
them um to be honest in my case it it I
他们？说实话，就我而言，我
don't think it hits them that hard
觉得对他们的影响并不大，
because most things usually fall on me
因为大多数事情通常都落在我身上，
and people want to go after me because
人们想攻击我，因为
I'm the guy that does good the quotquot
我是个做好事的人，是个“
philanthropist so usually I'm like the
慈善家”，所以通常我就是那个
one that gets thrown under the bus quite
被推下水的人。
a bit it's funny cuz I everyone that
这很有趣，因为所有
knows you
认识你的人都
knows you yeah whether they're really
知道你，是的，无论是
successful people or people that you
成功人士还是你的同事，我都和他们聊过，所有
that knows you knows who you are and
认识你的人都知道你是谁。
it's it's remarkable to me that um
对我来说，这很不可思议，一个为
world I've looked at your philanthropy I
世界做了这么多好事的人，我了解你的慈善事业，我
know what you you're doing with Feasta
知道你和Feasta
BS and the ethical sourcing of that when
BS合作的项目，以及你对道德采购的坚持。当
I see someone that's done so much good
我看到一个为世界做了这么多好事的人
in the world still be misunderstood it
仍然被误解时，这
almost makes it almost makes me realize
几乎让我感到…… 我意识到
that I should never fight it yeah I mean
我永远不应该反抗，是的，我的意思是，讽刺的
the ironic part is the more I help
是，我帮助
people the more [__] I get to be honest
别人越多，我受到的批评就越多。说实话，这真的很好
like it's it's so funny because you know
笑，因为你知道，
like the same day I'll uh drop a video
就像同一天，我发布了一个视频，
where I'll uh uh you know help a
帮助
thousand blind people see some other
一千个盲人重见光明，而另一个
YouTuber will drop a video where they
YouTuber发布了一个视频，展示他们刚买
just bought a new mansion and it's like
了一栋新豪宅，
everyone's like yes you know get that
每个人都说“是啊，买豪宅，干得
Mansion good job and then they'll be
好”，然后他们又会说“去你的，你
like [__] you for curing blind people
治好了盲人，
Jimmy [__] you you're using them and I'm
吉米，去你的，你在利用他们”，而我却说“
like no I just wanted to inspire people
不，我只是想激励人们
to do good I mean you can buy a mansion
行善”，我的意思是，
if you really want me to um so it is
如果你真的想让我买豪宅，我可以给你买。所以这很
funny I if you're trying this is a weird
讽刺。如果你想获得点赞，这
sentence but if you're trying to be
句话可能有点奇怪，但如果你想获得点赞，
liked I actually don't recommend you
我其实不建议你
like help people like I actually think
帮助别人。事实上，我认为
helping people will make the internet
帮助别人反而会让网络更不喜欢
like you less than if you just like buy
你，不如你买
nice cars and do like the the typical
豪车，走典型的
influencer path it's because they we
网红路线。这是因为
just so conditioned in America to see it
在美国，人们已经被灌输了一种观念，认为帮助别人就像是一种
as like a shield and like no one
保护伞。 显然，没人
actually does good cuz they just find it
真正做好事，因为他们只是觉得
fun apparently um but I mean I don't
好玩。嗯，不过我不在乎，
care I like I said it's just more fun
就像我说的，做总比不做事有趣。
than if I didn't so I mean people can
所以，别人可以因为我
[__] on me for helping people I don't I
帮助别人而骂我，我不在乎，我真的不在乎了。
don't doesn't bother me anymore um but I
嗯，但
wouldn't recommend you get into it if
如果
you want to be liked because I think
你想被人喜欢，我建议你别做，因为我觉得
it's negatively correlated now
这和受欢迎程度呈负相关。
interesting it is so fascinating it is I
这很有意思，太迷人了，我
swear to God man
发誓，伙计，
like people it's it's it's uh there I
就像人们那样，嗯，嗯，嗯，我
could just uh I don't know do these like
可以做些“
uh $1 versus videos where I compare like
1美元对比”之类的视频，比如把
a $1 boat to a billion dollar boat and
1美元的船和10亿美元的船做比较，或者做
all these other things not help people
其他一些不帮助别人的事，这样
and I would just get way less [__] and
我受到的批评就会少得多。这
it's it's so funny cuz no one bats an
很搞笑，因为
eye when I post that but when I give
我发那些视频的时候没人说什么，但当我给
Africa clean drinking water it's like
非洲成千上万的人提供干净的饮用水时，就好像
all hell breaks loose and I'm like guys
世界末日来临了一样。我就想说，伙计们，
I'm just trying to bring attention to a
我只是想让人们关注一个
cause I don't really but the thing is
事业，我真的没有别的意思。但问题是……
I'm just GNA keep doing it and I mean I
我只是继续做下去，我的意思是，我
think in my case most people have
觉得就我而言，大多数人都
realized I'm not going to stop so
意识到我不会停下来，所以
they're just kind of over you know
他们已经不再生气了，他们会说，好吧，
all right Jimmy's just being Jimmy I
吉米就是吉米。我
think when the wind blows as well what
觉得风吹过之后，它的作用是
it does is it helps you to really
帮助你真正
understand why you're doing what you're
理解你为什么做你正在做的事情，也让你更
doing and understand yourself mhm and so
了解自己。嗯，所以
when I've been attacked for like the
当我因为
people I interview or whatever it might
采访对象或其他什么原因受到攻击时，它
be it's actually made me refocus on what
实际上让我重新专注于
my principles are yeah because you have
我的原则是什么。因为你必须
to be really anchored to them it's like
真正坚守这些原则，就像
I said you you have to know where your
我说的，你必须知道你的
line is and as long as you're on the
底线在哪里，只要你站在
right side of your line then it is what
底线的正确一侧，那就没关系。
it is people on Twitter can say whatever
推特上的人想说什么就说什么，
they want and I I think like that's the
我认为这是
only way to really survive at this scale
在这个规模下生存而
without going crazy is you you have to
不至于崩溃的唯一方法，你必须
determine where the line is not let the
确定底线在哪里，不要让
internet
网络
workaholism yes can can you give me a
工作狂左右你。是的，你能给我描述一下你
window into the last seven days of your
过去七天的
life just give me paint me a picture oh
生活吗？给我描绘一下，哦，
yes uh let me uh drink some water cuz my
是的。 呃，让我喝点水，因为我得了
flu well the I don't know about the last
流感。嗯，过去七天的情况我不太清楚，
seven days but in general we uh so we're
但总的来说，我们正在
filming a video where we're doing the
拍摄一个视频，内容是
I'm visiting the five most deadliest
探访地球上五个最危险的
places on Earth so one of the places was
地方。其中一个地方是
a safari in South Africa so I flew to
南非的野生动物园，所以我飞到
South Africa um to spend time in a cage
南非，在一个被狮子包围的笼子里待了一段时间，真是太棒了。不过去那里可真不容易。
get to and then I got the flu and so
然后我得了流感，
spent a couple days in the hospital
在医院住了几天。
there um and then we were going to go to
之后我们本来要去
Snake Island to spend time there then
蛇岛，然后去
the W's deadliest Road and then we have
W最危险的公路，还有
a couple other places but that got
几个其他地方，但是都被
postponed so instead got out of the
推迟了。所以我出院后
hospital went to Florida filmed with
去了佛罗里达，和
Aaron judge then I went to or no went to
Aaron Judge一起拍摄。然后我又去了
North Carolina we have this guy where I
北卡罗来纳州。我在那里帮一个人
built a gym and I told him if he loses
建了一个健身房，我跟他说，如果
100 pounds before he leaves the gym it
他在离开健身房之前减掉100磅（健身房
has a big red circle around it I'll give
周围有个大红圈），我就给
him a bunch of money so I filmed with
他一大笔钱。所以我跟
him then worked on the coming up videos
他一起拍摄，然后…… 接下来的视频……
um that just a lot and then flew to
嗯，很多，然后飞到
Florida filmed with Aaron judge flew
佛罗里达和亚伦·贾奇一起拍摄，飞到
here just landed filmed with the reunion
这里，刚落地，和你一起拍摄了
for Beast games we're doing this podcast
野兽游戏参赛者的重聚。我们正在做这个播客，现在几点了？凌晨
what time is it like 1:00 a it's just
1点？快到凌晨
off to 1: a.m yeah 1: a the latest
1点了。是的，凌晨1点。
podcast he's ever done lightweight I
他最近做的播客是《轻量级》。我
always do my podcast at 1: a.m um my
总是凌晨1点做播客。嗯，我上
last podcast before this was like 4 a.m.
一次做播客是凌晨4点，大概是
um like like a couple weeks ago and then
几周前。然后，
uh we're flying to San FR to film with
我们要飞到旧金山和斯蒂芬一起拍摄。
Steph then we're Steph Curry yeah Steph
我们是斯蒂芬·库里，对，斯蒂芬·
Curry then I think I'm going to Snake
库里。然后我想我会去
Island then the deadliest Road um and
蛇岛，然后是《致命之路》。嗯，
then I I won't I'll basically I don't
然后我……基本上，我
think I'll be home for another 16 days
想我至少还要16天才能回家，
so I'm just traveling around filming for
所以我
the next 16 days and then um yeah I
接下来16天都在到处旅行拍摄。然后……嗯，我
guess then I'll get home and then
想之后我会回家，然后
they'll make me film at home how does
他们会让我在家拍摄。
everything else in your life fit into
其他方面怎么样？ 在你的生活中，
that in terms of like the gym I know
比如去健身房，我知道
you've been working out a it's been
你一直在锻炼，但
brutal it's gone to [__] the last couple
最近几个月简直糟透了，真的让
months it's just it's really killing me
我很崩溃。说
to be honest it's it was like so much
实话，以前
easier when you're bro if you don't
如果你不用
constantly life is so easy when you just
经常出差，生活会轻松得多。每天早上
wake up in your own bed and like waking
醒来就能躺在自己的床上，
up in your own bed and working 15 hours
然后在办公室或其他地方工作15个小时，这
easy compared to like all this [__]
比现在这些
[__] where I'm like I don't know the
乱七八糟的事情轻松多了。我不知道自己在哪个
time zone I'm in I don't know what place
时区，不知道自己在哪儿，
I'm in I don't know where I'm going in
也不知道两天后要去哪儿。有时候我早上
I'm going to bed at 10:00 a.m. other
10点就睡觉，
days I'm going to bed at 5:00 p.m. and
有时候下午5点才睡。 感觉
it's like it's a mess it's really and I
一团糟，真的。我以前还能忍受，还能想办法完成
training but it's just I don't I don't I
训练，但现在我真的不
don't know I need to truthfully whatever
知道该怎么办了。说实话，
is a priority you'll get done I just
我
need to make it a priority again because
需要重新把训练放在优先位置，因为
I really do miss it it's just this the
我真的很想念它。难就难在要兼顾
hard part is putting putting Beast games
Beast Games，
in the mix because I was already like
因为我之前
basically working you know whatever
基本上
every hour my eyes were away but then
每时每刻都在忙，眼睛都离不开它。Beast
Beast games is such a monster of a
Games是个庞然大物，
project and I have to maintain the same
我还要保持
Youtube upload schedule and then I do a
YouTube的上传频率，
lot on fetival now and then I have a
现在还要忙Fetival，还有
couple other businesses so I I just
其他几家公司，所以说
honestly something had to to give and
实话，我必须做出取舍。
sadly it was working out but it's
可悲的是，之前勉强还能应付，但这真的
[__] stupid so I need to like rep
太蠢了。所以我需要重新
prioritize my life where I can get I
调整生活，尽可能地挤出时间来训练，哪怕
mean it just only needs to be 45 minutes
只是
5 days a week it does doesn't need to be
每周5天，每天45分钟也好，不需要
hard but the bigger problem is I'm just
太难。但更大的问题是，
not sleeping like I used to because we
因为事情
got so much going on and so when I hit
太多，我睡眠严重不足。 当我
it hard in the gym and then I don't get
在健身房拼命训练，然后
enough sleep then that causes pretty
睡眠不足时，
extreme fatigue the next day so it's
第二天就会非常疲惫，所以我觉得
like I got to fix sleep first before
我得先解决睡眠问题。说实话，最近事情
that but yeah it's uh got a lot going on
很多，
to be honest I'm dying how are you
我感觉快要崩溃了。你
feeling uh right now honestly fine I'm
现在感觉怎么样？嗯，说实话，还好，我喝了
jacked up on a lot of caffeine but I
很多咖啡因，精神抖擞。但是，
mean just in in this Feast you know the
你知道，流感让
everything like 30% harder so you know
一切都变得更难了，大概增加了30%的难度。所以，
it's like life's like a roller coaster
生活就像过山车，总会有那么一些
there are going to be moments where like
时刻。
right now I'm going to answer this
我现在要回答这个问题，
negatively but I don't want someone to
但我不想让别人
think that's indicative of like oh every
觉得
and every time you ask me this it's
每次你问我这个问题，我的回答都是负面的。
going to be it but because of the flu
只是因为流感
and the lack of sleep I mean I'm
和睡眠不足，我现在很
struggling at the moment just a lot of
挣扎，一直在努力。
grinding um a little happy because we
嗯，有点高兴，因为我们
just dropped the ending of Beast game so
刚刚发布了《Beast》游戏的结局，所以现在有点
it's like a little bit of emotional high
情绪高涨。
but after this I'm probably going to go
但之后我可能就会
crashed be tired as [__] in the morning
崩溃了。
tomorrow which I hate um but yeah I
明天早上肯定累得要死，我讨厌这样。嗯，我
would say I'm on like the lower end I I
感觉自己状态不太好，需要好好休息
could use a couple good days to bring
几天才能
the energy back up quick one I want to
恢复精力。我想
talk about something we all need to take
谈谈一个我们都必须
seriously which is cyber security
认真对待的问题：网络安全。
whether you're a firsttime Founder
无论你是初次创业
facing your very first audit or a
面临审计的创始人，还是经验
seasoned professional who's been through
丰富的专业人士，
it all staying compliant is getting more
合规都变得
critical than ever and more complicated
比以往任何时候都更加重要，也更加复杂。Vant 正是为此而
comes in who is a sponsor of this
生的，它是本播客的赞助商。Vant 可以
podcast vant takes the pain out of
简化
security compliance autom ating the
安全合规流程，自动执行
tedious but essential process of proving
繁琐但至关重要的流程，证明
your business is secure across over 35
你的企业在 35 多个
Frameworks like sock 2 ISO
框架（例如 SOCKS 2 和 ISO
271 centralize your workflows answer
271）中都是安全的。它可以集中你的工作流程，以
security questions up to five times
高达五倍的速度回答安全问题，
faster and protect your business without
并在不影响业务增长的情况下保护你的企业。
losing focus on growth and this is
这
really a critical part of this a new IDC
确实至关重要。IDC 的一份新
white paper found that companies using
白皮书发现，使用
van save over
Van 的公司每年可以节省超过
$535,000 a year and it pays for itself
53.5 万美元，而且
in just 3 months for a limited time my
只需 3 个月就能收回成本。限时优惠：访问
v.com that's
v.com 即可获得 1000 美元折扣。 在
van.com for $1,000 off how do you think
van.com 上购物可享 1000 美元折扣。你如何
about mental health I've heard you speak
看待心理健康？我之前听你谈过
about your mental health before and I've
你的心理健康，
yeah I don't well the thing is here's
嗯，我不太了解。问题是，
the problem like it's uh if my mental
如果我的心理
health was a party I wouldn't be as
健康像一场派对，我就不会像现在这样
successful as I am I mean and that's
成功。我的意思是，这只是一个令人
just like a sad fact um like I obviously
难过的事实。显然，我永远不会把
never would have buried myself alive for
自己活埋好
S days s days of solitary s days on a
几天，在荒岛上独自待上好几天，
deserted island 7 days blah blah blah um
7 天等等等等。
it's it's like you know being
你知道，
consistently uncomfortable and like cons
持续的不适感，以及能够
long periods is like arguably one of the
长期持续地承受痛苦，可以说是最
deepest modes like there's a reason no
深刻的体验之一。这就是为什么没有人像
one makes videos like me like not even
我一样制作视频，甚至没有一个能与之
close because no one wants to live the
媲美，因为没有人想过我这样的
life I live I mean there there are
生活。我的意思是，有些
months where I'm you know I think there
月份，你知道，我想有
was one year I was flying like 200 days
一年我大概有 200 天都在
like I was on a plane I mean it was it
飞机上，那简直是
was a [__] fest but you know to get
一场噩梦，但你知道，为了
these videos done and and I do
完成这些视频，我什么都做。
everything and it's like you know when I
你知道，就像我
when I wake up tomorrow and I'm going to
明天醒来，肯定会累得要死，
be pretty [__] tired and feel like
感觉
[__] I'm going to go you know I
糟透了，但
something I always tell myself is how
我会告诉自己，
you feel right now is why no one else
你现在的感受正是别人做不到
does what you want to do or does what
你想做的事或做不到
you do and if you push through this
你正在做的事的原因。如果你能坚持下去，那就更能说明
reason why no one will ever be who you
为什么没人能成为你。
are and so it's like I think being able
所以我觉得，能够
to push through unhappiness and do
克服不快乐，年复一年、持续十年地去做
things you don't want to do consistently
自己不想做的事，这才是
decade is like the ultimate Advantage
真正的优势。
like I mean I I think we'll hit a
我的意思是，我觉得我们能达到
billion subscribers and uh I don't think
十亿订阅量，而且我觉得没
anyone will be anywhere near close
人能接近这个数字。
because like once you make a couple
因为一旦你赚了几
million dollars why would you live the
百万美元，你为什么还要过
life I live like why why would you not
我现在的生活？为什么你不
take weekends off why would you not just
休息周末？为什么你不选择在
film locally even if it means less views
本地拍摄，即使这意味着观看量会减少，
so you can be on the right time schedule
这样你才能按时完成拍摄？
why would you not you know prioritize
为什么你不优先考虑
your sanity and that kind of stuff it
自己的精神状态等等？这听起来
makes no sense but that's why no one
毫无道理，但这就是为什么
else does it you spoke to Colin inir two
别人做不到的原因。你和科林聊过吗？
guys that I met recently um great great
我最近认识了两个人，嗯，他们
great guys um you said to them I'm
人真的很好。你跟他们说我很多
miserable a lot of times I have mental
时候都很痛苦，我几乎
breakdowns every other
每隔一周就会精神崩溃一次。是的，我的情况好多了。
little better mental break down sounds
精神崩溃听起来有点夸张，其实更像是“我去，
extreme it's more I'm like [__] why am I
我为什么要
doing this this is so [__] hard um
这么做？这太他妈难了！”
cuz it's just a lot man you're just
因为事情太多了，你得不停地
going constantly It's like because
忙下去。
what's funny is I think I said that
有趣的是，我觉得我
years ago but that was back when all I
几年前也说过类似的话，但那时候我
was really was doing YouTube now I run
基本上只做YouTube。现在我经营
this chocolate company and we have the
一家巧克力公司，我们还有
show and we have a couple other stuff so
节目，还有其他一些事情要做。所以
I think the the hardest part really is
我觉得最难的部分其实是
gear shifting like and so I try to
切换工作。所以我尽量把
bucket these things correct like if if
这些事情分类整理好。比如，如果
I'm on set you know and I have a 15-
我在片场，你知道，
Hour film day like ideally the thing I'm
一天要拍15个小时，理想情况下，我会把
doing in between filming or like related
拍摄间隙的时间用来做和
to main Channel because I'm in the frame
主频道相关的事情，因为我当时的心态是专注于主频道的。
of mind of that and that's one thing
这
that's really helped me not feel like my
真的帮我避免了崩溃的感觉。比如，
head's going to explode like if I'm in
如果我在
Chicago at the febles office and we're
芝加哥的Febles办公室，我就不会觉得头要爆炸了。 我们
going through febles marketing like and
正在进行一些市场营销方面的讨论，
then you come in and you go what do you
然后你进来问我对
think about this bit for this coming up
即将发布的
main Channel video then I have to like
主频道视频的这个部分有什么看法。这时我不得不
shift my frame of mind and like that
转换思路，这种
constant gear shifting I it like it'll
不断切换的状态真的
make my [__] head hurt if I'm like
会让我头疼，如果我这样来回切换
bouncing around too much I and it it
太多次的话。而且这真的
also just very not quarter I am I love
不是我喜欢的那种状态。我喜欢
obsessing over certain things and I find
专注于某些事情，但我发现，
you know obsessing over things within a
专注于某个
business isn't like switching back and
业务领域的事情并不像在市场
forth between marketing and product and
营销和产品之间来回切换
a same business is pretty easy there's a
那么容易。
long way of saying like one thing that's
说了这么多，其实有一件事对我有
helped with that is like just really um
帮助，那就是合理
organizing my schedule and away where it
安排我的日程，
allows my natural state of mind to like
让我能够自然而然地
obsess over a certain business finish
专注于某个业务，完成
that then move on to the next one
之后再进行下一个。
whereas before it used to be like 30
而以前我
gear Swit shs a day and that that's just
一天要切换30次，那简直太
miserable it's just not even fun to be
痛苦了，说实话，一点乐趣都没有。
honest I had um Elon mus C I know
我认识埃隆·马斯克，
someone you you spoke about quite often
你经常提到他，我也
often I heard him say when he was on Joe
经常提到他。我听他说过…… 他上乔·
Rogan that you wouldn't want to be in my
罗根的节目时说，你肯定不想了解我的
head and I think joean asked him if he
内心。我记得乔问他是否
was happy or something and he doesn't
快乐之类的，但他似乎并不
even like consider the question to be
觉得这个问题
important yeah so two questions there do
重要。所以，这里有两个问题：
you think the average person would like
你觉得普通人会想了解
to be in your head and
你的内心吗？
secondly are you happy uh well no the
其次，你快乐吗？嗯，不，
average person does not want to live the
普通人不想过我这样的
life I live or be in my head they they
生活，也不想了解我的内心。他们会很
would be miserable because you're just
痛苦，因为你一直在
working all the time and they they would
工作。他们可能会
probably just ask themselves why am I
问自己：我为什么要一直
working all the time why don't I why
工作？为什么
don't I do literally anything else I
不做点别的？我的
mean because there I mean obviously I'm
意思是，我当然
not a robot there are times where I'm
不是机器人。有时候我会想：
like [__] I really want to play this
我真想玩这个
strategy board game I want to do this
策略棋盘游戏，或者做点别的
thing and I'm I look at the schedule I'm
事。然后我看看日程安排，
like oh maybe I could do that in four
心想：哦，也许我四天就能完成。
days and you you know and the the hard
你知道，难就难在
thing is it's you really have to like be
你必须
delicate with the framing of your mind
小心翼翼地控制自己的思维模式，
because it's very easy in moments like
因为在那种时候很容易觉得
that to go [__] I'm like a zoo animal
自己像动物园里的动物一样。 难道
like I don't I don't have free will I'm
我没有自由意志吗？我
like a little robot to my businesses and
就像个小机器人，被我的事业牵着鼻子走。
um and so you have to like be very
所以你必须非常
careful and sometimes those emotions
小心，有时候这些情绪会
take over and especially because I'm a
占据上风，尤其是我这种
very defiant kind of guy and I'm like
比较叛逆的人，我会想：
but I really want to do this thing but I
我真的很想做这件事，但我
can't because I got to go film this
做不到，因为我得去拍
video and I got to do this and I got to
视频，我得做这个，我得去
speak at this conference and I got to do
参加这个会议，我得去参加
this networking thing and blah blah and
这个社交活动，等等等等。
so um yeah I think most people when that
所以，嗯，我觉得大多数人在这种
feeling comes up of like am I just a
感觉出现的时候——比如“我难道只是个
[__] animal like do I have any free
动物吗？我还有自由
will they would probably get very
意志吗？”——可能会非常
depressed and but I've been able to like
沮丧。但我已经能够克服
work through those and and just I always
这些情绪了。我总是努力
you just got to control your thoughts be
控制自己的想法，告诉自己：
like well this is the life I chose this
这是我选择的生活，我想要
is you want success you want to change
成功，我想要改变
the world you want to do this and this
世界，你想要做这件事，
this is the price you have to pay you
这就是你必须付出的代价。你
should actually see this as a good thing
应该把这看作是一件好事，
because this is why which is why I'm
因为这就是为什么我
very uh diligent about how I frame
非常注重自己
things in my mind like this is why no
思维方式的原因。 这就是为什么没
one else will do what you will do and
人会做你想做的事，而
this is a good thing this is what you
这是一件好事。你
are feeling right now is your Mo it's
现在感受到的就是你的动力，
you're lucky it's hard push through it
你很幸运。虽然很难，但坚持下去，
and you'll be happy you did you know and
你会庆幸自己做到了。这就是
so that's kind of how I try to
我
view it um but no I don't think most
看待这件事的方式。嗯，但我不认为大多数
people would be happy living my life
人会喜欢我这样的生活，
they would be like oh let's just grab a
他们会说：“哦，我们去拿
couple million dollars and be happy are
几百万美元，然后快乐地生活吧。”
you happy uh it depends what day you ask
你快乐吗？嗯，这取决于你哪天问
me right now I'm having a good time um
我。我现在过得很好。嗯，
other you know when I was had the flu in
你知道，还有我在
Africa sitting in a cage of allance [__]
非洲得流感，被关在笼子里的时候，那可就糟透了。
no so what's your Baseline how would you
所以你的基线是什么？你会如何
describe your Baseline probably uh this
描述你的基线？可能，嗯，
year probably so far more unhappy than
今年到目前为止，不快乐多于
happy and it's just they're just things
快乐。有些事情
you got to do that just aren't fun you
你必须去做，但它们并不有趣。
know but I I think I I really deeply
但我认为，我真的非常
enjoy working on feasts and I'm trying
享受筹备盛宴的工作，我正在努力把
to spend more of my time building it the
更多的时间花在筹备上。
problem is it's just I uh it's just
问题是，嗯，这只是
opportunity cost because I'm the only
机会成本，因为我是…… 只有
one who can be in front of the camera
一个人能站在镜头前
and film and that's what's like brutal
拍摄，这才是最残酷的地方，
especially with Beast games is I'm just
尤其是在Beast Games，我
filming so much it added so much [__] to
拍摄的内容太多了，这给
my yearly filming like doing this giant
我的年度拍摄工作增加了太多负担，比如除了运营
largest YouTube channel the world I was
全球最大的YouTube频道之外，还要做这个大型节目。我
already filming some months 25 days a
之前几个月甚至要拍摄25天，
month so I'm just like that's just the
所以我觉得这才是
rough part is because it's like it just
最难的部分，因为这就像把
all rests my shoulders and if I don't
所有的精力都压在了我的肩上，如果我不
film there is no content like the
拍摄，频道就没有内容了，就好像真的
channel just literally ceases like if I
停播了一样。
stop filming and so you know I I have
你知道，我
found more and more that I'm finding
越来越发现，我
more joy in entrepreneurial things and
在创业和创建公司方面找到了更多乐趣，
I'd be happier if I could spend more
如果能花更多
time doing that but it's just like weird
时间做这些，我会更快乐。但这很奇怪，
because I could literally hire anyone in
因为我可以雇佣世界上任何人来做
the world to do that whereas I can't
这些，但我却找不到
hire anyone to replace me on camera I
人来代替我出镜。我
always wonder someone who um is doing so
总是好奇，那些在
well on a platform like YouTube where
YouTube这种
the algorithm is always changing MH so
算法不断变化的平台上做得如此成功的人是怎么做到的。
many YouTubers I speak to say that they
我跟很多YouTuber聊过，他们都说
get burnout eventually they get like
最终会感到疲惫，会陷入
creative burnout and they and they just
创作瓶颈。 他们就
like delete their Channel you've seen a
直接删频道，你
lot of it recently over the last couple
最近
years where YouTubers hit 10 million and
几年经常看到这种情况，很多油管博主粉丝破千万就停更了。是啊，你有没有想过
your mind to stop oh of course I mean
放弃？哦，当然，我经常这么想，真的。
like I this I feel like that's what half
我觉得
this podcast has been about about how I
这期播客有一半的内容都是在讲这个，讲的是我不想
don't want to do things but I push
做某件事，但我还是坚持做了。
through and do it I think they're just
我觉得他们都是
reasonable humans like they you know a
很正常的人，你知道，他们很多人都在
lot of them were chasing a goal of like
追求某个目标，比如“
oh I just want this money so I can take
我想要钱，这样我就可以
care of this things you know it could be
照顾好这些事”，你知道，这可能是很
Noble things like retire my mom or just
崇高的目标，比如让我妈妈退休，或者只是
not have to worry about money and then
不用再为钱发愁。然后
they go why would I suffer now I'm good
他们就想，我为什么要受苦呢？我现在过得很好。你
when was the closest you came to
最接近放弃是什么时候？
quitting oh man probably countless times
哦，天哪，可能数不清了，
I mean all when I was in solitary
我是说，在我被单独
confinement for seven days I mean that
监禁七天的时候，那真是太
was [__] miserable I mean I did quit
痛苦了。我的确放弃过一个
a video well I've quit a lot of videos
视频，嗯，我放弃过很多视频。
like no I mean as a as a Creator um I
不，我是说作为一个创作者，嗯，
mean I guess I never truly would have
我想我从来没有真正想过
quit I mean my biggest thing would be I
放弃。 我的意思是，我最想做的就是
just would have quit for like a week and
辞职休息一个星期，心想“去他妈的，
been like [__] let me sleep nine hours a
让我每天睡九个小时吧”。
night and like um but like I spent the
但是，我们之前拍过
fir we we did a video where we spent
一个视频，讲的是
seven days on a desert island first time
在荒岛上待七天。第一次
we filmed it on day two I woke up on the
拍摄的时候，第二天我醒来发现自己躺在
beach and I had literally I didn't know
沙滩上，我以前都不知道有
sand fleas were a thing I had like 700
沙蚤这种东西，
bug bites up and down my legs all over
腿上、身上到处都是虫咬的包，大概有700个。
my body I was sunburned I was like a
我晒伤了，身上还有点皮疹。
little bit of meal I was like damn am I
我当时就想，天哪，我会不会
going to die like this is crazy how much
死？这太疯狂了，
like bug bites are everywhere and my
到处都是虫咬的包，
skin was so red and I was I couldn't see
皮肤红得像番茄，眼睛都睁不开。
straight and so I ended up quitting on
所以，第二天我就辞职了。
day two um which is brutal cuz you spend
这太残酷了，因为你花了那么多
all this time and money and you have the
时间和金钱，还有
crew out there and you flew out there
工作人员，你飞过去，
and you know it's it's opportunity cost
你知道，这就是机会成本。本来
it's like that's a 7-Day window we could
我们可以用这七天时间拍完
have got a video and uploaded it and now
视频上传的，现在却
we don't like it's you know canceling
不得不取消，
video like that is literally the worst
这简直是最糟糕的
thing that could happen from an
事情。 从机会成本的角度来看，这种情况可能会发生。
was like you know and you have moments
你知道，有时候你会遇到这样的时刻，感觉就像“
like those and it's like [__] like this
操，这根本
isn't even fun [__] this [__] you know
不好玩，操，这破事儿”，你知道吗？
but but what about YouTube as a whole
但是YouTube整体上又如何呢？
because I feel like YouTube is like
因为我觉得YouTube就像往
throwing coal into a train then you just
火车里扔煤，
have to keep throwing it in there once
一旦开始就必须不停地扔，根本停不下来。就像在
treadmill CR up to the max especially if
跑步机上拼命跑，尤其是如果
you want to be a top tier creater like
你想成为像我这样的顶级创作者，那就更是如此。
me and it's just like who who can stay
这就像比拼谁能
on the treadmill the longest cuz it
在跑步机上坚持最久，因为它永远
never slows down if anything you're
不会慢下来，反而越跑
making it faster um but no I mean I
越快。嗯，我的意思是，
time where I actually would have quit it
我从未真正想过放弃，
just breaks probably would have been
只是它坏了可能
nice and when you think forward that
挺好的。当你展望未来，
treadmill can you see yourself doing it
你觉得你会在
for the next two three four decades or
接下来的二三十年甚至四十年里一直跑下去吗？哦，
oh yeah of course I don't have any
当然，我根本没
intention of ever stopping okay um love
打算停下来。嗯，我喜欢
couple of years ago y you announced I
几年前出现在我生活中的一件事，你宣布，我
think over Christmas time that you had
想是在圣诞节期间……
proposed I think it was like Boxing Day
我记得好像是在节礼日
or New Year's Eve yeah it was on
或者新年夜求婚的，哦，对，是
Christmas day oh Christmas Day because
圣诞节那天，因为
her family was in town so I proposed
她家人都在城里，所以我求婚了。
okay how does that fit into this
好吧，这跟我这
craziness she's literally I you could
疯狂的求婚经历有什么关系呢？她真的是，你一只手就能
probably count on your hands the amount
数过来
of uh people on the planet that actually
地球上能成为
would make a good partner for me and
我理想伴侣的人，而
she's just she's just one of them she
她就是其中之一。她
really understands that work is what you
真的理解工作是我的生命，是我的动力，
going and she supports me and she
她支持我，她
understands how important it is and it's
明白工作对我有多重要。
the big thing is hanging out with Tia my
最重要的是，和我的
fiance is is so frictionless we play the
未婚妻蒂娅在一起非常轻松自在。我们玩
same video games we watch the same shows
同样的电子游戏，看同样的剧，对
we're very interested in the same things
同样的事情很感兴趣。
she loves learning like I do so um you
她和我一样热爱学习，所以，你
know it's exciting to see what you know
知道，看到
um lecture she listened to online that
她那天在网上听了什么讲座，
day or like whatever weird book she's
或者在读什么奇奇怪怪的书，真的很令人兴奋。
reading and she just like everything
和她在一起的一切都
about being around her is very
非常
frictionless which is great because like
轻松自在，这很棒，因为很
obvious I don't have much time at the
明显，我没多少时间待在
house and so like the last thing that I
家里，所以我最不想的
need is to come home from work and there
就是下班回家后……
be friction and so we don't we don't
会有摩擦，所以我们不
fight it's I you know I sometimes I'm
吵架。你知道，有时候我会想，
like wow this is like my best friend
哇，这简直就是我最好的朋友，
this and she's hot this is great you
而且她还很漂亮，这太棒了。你
know um and so it's like it it feels
知道吗？嗯，所以
weird sometimes
有时候感觉有点奇怪。
people I mean anyone in a listening now
我想，现在正在听的任何一个
that's in a relationship I guess the
恋爱中的人都会想，
question they'd be thinking is like when
你们什么时候在一起？
do you spend time together mostly at
主要是
nights um and the that but the beauty is
晚上吗？嗯，等等。但妙处在于，
she gears her schedule around mine so
她会根据我的时间安排来调整自己的时间。比如，
like she she'll work when um I'm working
她会在我工作的时候工作，
and then she'll just travel with me and
然后她会和我一起旅行。
so honestly a lot of it is on planes a
所以说实话，很多时候我们都在飞机上，很多时候都
lot of it's in car rides or you know an
在车上，或者你知道，
hour before bed or in the morning that
睡前一小时或者早上之
kind of stuff but it's like because
类的。因为
there are pockets of breaks on set and
在片场会有零碎的休息时间，
things like that so it's just you know
所以你知道，
having it's it's really hard to find
找到
someone who is intelligent actually has
一个既聪明又有
their own Hobbies things going for them
自己的爱好，
independent that's also willing to mold
独立自主，还愿意为了
their life around mine and not see it as
我而调整自己生活，并且不觉得这是
a demeaning thing because like yeah if
贬低自己的人真的很难。 如果
she was just like well I have this thing
她只是说“我还有事要忙，
going on and I have to prioritize my
我得优先考虑我的
life I would never see her but because
生活”，那我可能永远都不会见到她。但
she's willing to you know mold her life
她愿意为了我调整自己的生活，
around mine uh and my work schedule that
配合我的工作安排，
that you know is that's everything um
你知道，这就是一切。
and it's rare that someone's willing to
很少有人愿意这样
do that while you know being as in my
做。在我看来，
opinion at least from what I've seen as
至少从我所见，像
intelligent and independent as she is
她这样聪明独立的女性，
parents always message me and say Steve
父母总是给我发信息说：“史蒂夫，
wait till you have kids oh yeah that's
等你有了孩子再说吧。”哦，是啊，就是这样。我
right now is would not work for kids so
现在的生活方式不适合生孩子，所以
I want to wait want kids but I want to
我想要孩子，但我想尽可能晚一点再要。
wait as long as possible because if I'm
因为如果我要
going to have kids I got to be a great
孩子，我必须成为一个好
dad like I really I really really enjoy
爸爸。我真的很喜欢
mentoring people I love mentoring you
指导别人，我喜欢指导
know younger entrepreneurs and like help
年轻的创业者，帮助他们。
like I've told this I think I told the
就像我之前在
story on Joe Rogan I helped one of my
乔·罗根的节目里讲过的故事，我帮助我的一个
friends go from like 40K a month and
朋友在YouTube上的月收入从4万美元增长
revenue to 400k on YouTube and I do kind
到40万美元。我经常做类似的
of stuff like that all the time I just
事情。
like one of my other friends has a um
我的另一个朋友…… 我之前在一个
snack cpg brand and I helped them grow
零食消费品品牌工作，我帮他们实现了
to eight figures in Revenue just for fun
八位数的营收，纯粹是出于兴趣，
I would just call them a couple times a
我每个月会给他们打几次电话。
satisfying about helping other people
帮助别人
succeed and so I would love to have a
成功真的很有成就感，所以我很想生几个
couple kids and just like really Mentor
孩子，好好指导他们，把他们培养成很了不起的人。不过，
but yeah not anytime soon like I would
暂时不会有，如果
be so absent if we had kids so just got
有了孩子，我肯定会缺席很多。所以，
diagram where I could actually be
我得在
present in their life and your business
人生的某个阶段找到合适的时机，真正地陪伴他们成长。至于你的商业
Empire I think is much bigger than most
帝国，我觉得比大多数
people realize I imagine the majority of
人想象的要大得多。我想大多数
people probably don't really understand
人可能不太了解
the context of business so they don't
商业运作，所以不太明白。
really get it they might see you as a
他们可能把你当成一个
YouTuber or a Creator but from the
YouTube博主或者内容创作者。但根据
research that I've done you run
我的调查，你经营着
a very very large business yeah I mean
一家非常非常大的公司。是的，我们的营收是
we'll we do nine figures and feals I
九位数，
and feable
而且是相当可观的。
so the business must be worth several
所以，这家公司的总价值肯定有几十
billions of dollars uh overall I mean
亿美元。嗯，总的来说，
you could do do something like that yeah
你可以做到那样。是的，
I'm not going to get you to to try and
我不会让你去冒险
Hazard a guess I'm sure you know but I'm
猜测，我确定。 你知道，我
not going to get ask you to predict that
不会让你预测未来，
but
但是这家
but the business would be worth a lot of
公司肯定
money are you a billionaire uh on paper
价值连城。你是亿万富翁吗？嗯，账面上是的，
yeah but I mean in my actual bank
但我的银行
account I've BL a million dollars so do
账户里只有一百万美元。你会给自己发工资吗？
you pay yourself at all a little bit but
一点点，但
I also like I have some assistance and
我也有一些补助之类的，
things like that so it's like I try to
所以我尽量只给自己发工资，也就是我
personally a month just to like stay
每个月的开销，这样才能收支平衡。
even how how do you how do you think
你是怎么看待
about money and all of this because most
金钱的？因为
most people in their lives are pursuing
大多数人一生都在追求
money so that they can chill out and
金钱，以便退休后可以放松休息，
retire but you seem to be pursuing it
但你似乎
purely for the sake of reinvesting it
纯粹是为了把钱
back into the system money is fuel to
再投资到系统中。金钱是
grow a business and then you make money
发展业务的燃料，然后你
from the business and then keep growing
从业务中赚钱，然后继续发展。是的，然后
yeah and then you you find a business
你找到一个
that you enjoy that you know is better
你喜欢的、
for mother nature earth or people and
对地球母亲或人类有益的生意，这样
there you go you have a fulfilled life
你就拥有了充实的人生。
that's my theory I just don't when I'm
这就是我的理论。我只是
70 I don't want to look back and have
不想到了70岁的时候回头看时
regrets you know when is enough enough
后悔莫及。你知道，什么时候才算足够？这是一个
such a cliche question that I'm asked
老生常谈的问题。 我被问过太多次关于如何
enough enough like building the business
打造企业的问题了，
never I mean I just want to keep like
我的意思是，我只想说，
building a business is like a video game
打造企业就像玩电子游戏一样，很
it's it's just fun you know like with
有趣，你知道吗？就像
fbl right now um you know we're the
现在的FBL一样，嗯，你知道我们 我们是
company in America and like it's just
美国最大的符合道德标准的巧克力公司，
fun to like look at something that's
看着一个一
been done the same way for 100 years and
百年来一直沿用同样模式的东西，然后思考
go how do we just flip this on a Ted and
我们该如何颠覆它，彻底
[__] up this industry and you know how
改变这个行业，这本身就很有趣。你知道，
can we pay our Farmers a living income
我们该如何支付农民体面的收入，如何
you know not use child labor etc etc and
不使用童工等等。
so it's like you know I think if I was
所以，你知道，如果我
just doing mundane things like everyone
只是像其他人一样做些平淡无奇的事情，
else probably I probably would be bored
我可能会无聊透顶。如果
as [__] if I would just sold chocolate
我只是像其他人一样卖巧克力，
repetitive YouTube videos like everyone
像其他人一样制作千篇一律的YouTube视频，
else I probably would be like all right
我可能会想：好了，
get me out of this I want to retire but
让我离开这里，我想退休。但
it's not what we're doing like we're
我们现在做的不一样，我们正在
changing Industries we're impacting the
改变行业，我们正在影响世界。
life in my opinion you could do so much
在我看来，这就是人生的意义所在。你可以利用
with the gazillion people that list
数以亿计的订阅者、听众
listen and watch your videos you could
和观众做很多事情，你可以
like start almost any business and it be
创办几乎任何企业并取得
successful you could have almost any
成功，你可以产生几乎任何
social impact and it be profound and
社会影响，而且影响深远，甚至可以
save a gazillion people's lives do you
拯救无数人的生命。
do you struggle with Focus
你难以集中注意力吗？
uh no I mean I do wonder you know
嗯，不，我的意思是，我很好奇…… 我知道
sometimes should we be doing more but I
有时候我们应该做得更多，但我
I've really found a good Groove with
真的找到了制作巧克力的好方法，
febles I'm very I keep looking over
我一直在关注它，
there because there feasable sitting
因为它很实用。
there um I do feel like uh I've hit a
嗯，我感觉我找到了制作巧克力的
good Groove with that um and the ethical
好方法，还有
sourcing on it and the no I mean yeah
它的道德采购。不，我的意思是，是的，我当然
obviously I get a bajillion
有很多
opportunities but just you know right
机会，但你知道，
now this like I I think I said earlier
现在，就像我之前说的，
this is one of the few things in life
这是生活中为数不多的几件事之一，它
that i' I've it's scratched the same
满足了我做
itch as YouTube where building febles is
YouTube视频的相同需求，制作巧克力和
equally as fun as making videos for me
制作视频对我来说一样有趣。
it is so delicious thank you they're so
它太美味了，谢谢，它们太
delicious I'd really love to just spend
美味了。我真的很想
a moment talking about the ethical
花点时间谈谈道德
sourcing piece because I don't think
采购，因为我觉得
that's something I didn't understand
这是
until I did some research on you yeah
我在研究你之前不理解的。嗯，
um why why does that matter so much and
为什么它如此重要？
what when you say ethical sourcing
你说的道德采购是什么意思？
what's the difference between what you
你
do and what normal chocolate big
做的和
chocolate in America uh well the big
美国普通巧克力有什么区别？嗯，最重要的
thing is when I got into chocolate I
是，当我开始做巧克力的时候，
didn't I didn't know any of these things
我什么都不知道。 以前
um we we used to Source our Coco from
我们从
Peru cacao um which you know ethical
秘鲁采购可可豆，你知道，秘鲁的可可豆
sourcing is not really an issue there
采购在道德方面没什么问题。
but the problem is majority of the
但问题是，
Wolves Coco comes from West Africa and
Wolves Coco 的大部分可可豆都来自西非。
so as we got bigger you know everyone's
随着我们规模的扩大，大家都说，
like hey you need to switch your supply
嘿，你们需要把供应
chain to West Africa I'm like cool um
链转移到西非。我当时就觉得，好啊。然后
and so then I started studying and
我就开始研究和
reading up about it and I um and I
阅读相关资料，我
noticed that 46% of Labor in West Africa
注意到西非可可农场46%的劳动力
on Cocoa Farms is child labor and I was
是童工。我当时就觉得，这肯定不对劲。
and then I started digging deeper and
然后我开始深入调查，结果发现，
deeper and I was like holy [__] it's
天哪，
just almost half a labor is child labor
童工竟然占了近一半的劳动力！
and so I started talking to all the big
于是我开始联系所有的大型
chocolate companies or not all of them
巧克力公司，或者说，
but as many as I could get a hold of and
尽可能多地联系他们。我问他们，
I was like so what what do you guys do
你们是怎么解决
about this whole child labor thing and
童工问题的？
they they constantly just telling me
他们总是告诉我，这就是现状，
chocolate always has been I was like
巧克力行业一直都是这样。我当时就想，
whoa you guys make like a billion
哇，你们
dollars a year in profit you don't you
每年利润都那么高，难道就看
don't see an issue with that being on
不到童工问题吗？ 问题在于，这事发生在
the back of little kids and they're like
小孩子身上，他们会说“
no you and then I you know I I have this
不，是你”。然后你知道，我有个很
crazy clip on I have a documentary guy I
疯狂的视频，有个纪录片摄影师，我
think you saw him Jeff who follows me
想你见过他，叫杰夫，他一直跟着我。
around crazy clip where I'm meeting with
视频里我正在和一个
big um I got to be as vague as possible
大供应商见面，嗯，我得尽量说得含糊一点，
cuz they're going to murder me got time
因为他们会杀了我的。我得把时间还给
back to them but like a big supplier
他们，总之就是一个大供应商，
we'll just leave it big like that and I
我们就说到这儿吧。我
asked them I was like so do you have any
问他们，
way I can pay extra to not use child
我能不能额外付费，让他们不雇用童工之类的，或者有没有什么其他
options and they were just like no and I
选择？他们就说没有。当时
was and I my literal documentary guy is
我的纪录片摄影师正在
just like filming and I'm in like this
拍摄，我在一个
big boardroom and I look at the camera
很大的会议室里，看着镜头，心想“我的
I'm like holy [__] they just said that
天哪，他们居然在
on camera and uh and so I did all this
镜头前这么说了”。然后我做了很多
research and it was just like yeah no
调查，结果就是，确实没有。
and especially in America like there
尤其是在美国，虽然有
there's some European chocolate brands
一些欧洲巧克力品牌会
that you know try but uh in America like
尝试，但在美国，真的
really no one really cared I mean
没人真正在意这个问题。我的意思是，
there's plenty of options and plenty of
有很多选择，也有足够的时间、
time to fix it plenty of money to fix it
足够的钱来解决这个问题。 说实话，
so that just kind of honestly pissed me
这真的让我很生气，
off and like that so then I just was
所以我
like how do we solve this and so then it
就想，我们该怎么解决这个问题？然后我就陷入了
sent me down the rabbit hole the
沉思，
everything points back to like you know
所有的一切最终都指向同一个问题：你知道，
to the reason chocolate and America is
美国巧克力
so cheap is because they just don't you
这么便宜的原因，是因为他们根本没钱……你
know not the reason one of the reasons
知道，其中一个原因就是
they just pay the farmer so little like
他们付给农民的工资太低了，
Farmers make less than a dollar a day um
农民一天赚不到一美元。正
so like because of that they're forced
因为如此，他们被迫
to use child labor because I mean they
使用童工，因为他们
literally just don't even have money to
根本没钱
pay someone who's not a child how many
付给非儿童工人。
kids do you think are in child labor in
你觉得
West Africa just on Coco farms uh you
西非的可可种植园里有多少童工？你
might have so in that 5,000 no it's 1.5
可能觉得只有5000个？不，是150
million you're joking yeah it's over a
万个，你在开玩笑吧？超过100万个，太
million it's crazy so what we need to do
疯狂了！所以我们需要做的，在我看来，就是尽快实现
billion dollars a year in Revenue as
每年10亿美元的收入，
fast as possible while being ethically
同时还要保证采购符合道德标准，
sourced and being profitable big part of
并且盈利。其中很重要的一点
it is we have to be profitable while
是，我们必须在盈利的同时做到
doing it because then I can point and go
这一点，因为这样我就可以指着说，看，
look we achieve scale ethically and
我们实现了规模化，而且符合道德标准。
we're making money it's not that you
我们正在赚钱，不是你做不到，而是
can't do it you just don't want to and
你不想做。
then um and maybe maybe we give them the
然后，嗯，也许我们应该给他们一次机会，
benefit of a doubt maybe they just truly
也许他们真的
don't know how to do it at scale and
不知道如何大规模地做，也许这能让他们醒悟过来，他们会
be like oh I guess it is possible and
想，哦，原来是可以的，然后他们就会
they'll start to change the ways more
开始改变方式。不过，他们很
than likely they won't and I but over
可能不会改变。但
time I hope we can just shine a light on
我希望随着时间的推移，我们能
it using my platform and you know um
利用我的平台让更多人了解这件事，
just show the model works and then I
展示这种模式的可行性。然后，我
don't know something I would love to do
不知道，从长远来看，我最想做的一件事
in the long run is like you know how
是，你知道，就像
there's like the fair trade logo maybe I
公平贸易标志一样，也许我可以
make my own version of it and I help
设计一个自己的版本，帮助
other chocolate companies Source their
其他巧克力公司以符合
uh cacao ethically and uh or something
道德的方式采购可可豆，或者做些其他的事情。
and you know and I just educate people
你知道，我会教育人们，
on like if it doesn't have the symbol
如果产品没有这个标志，
it's probably using child labor and
很可能就使用了童工。
something I there's some way where I
我希望在未来十年里，我能找到一些方法，让
years where we get over a million kids
超过一百万的儿童
out of child labor uh on Coco farms and
摆脱可可种植园的童工困境。
so I just got to connect the dots and
我得把这些点串起来，
figure out the correct way to do it this
找出正确的方法。这听起来
might sound like a Prett obvious
可能像个显而易见的
question but it's it won't be to
问题，但并非
everybody why' you care so much bro I
每个人都这么想。兄弟，你为什么这么在意？我
just like I've been on these Farms I
只是觉得，我一直在这些农场里干活，我
don't want to get rich on the back of
不想靠剥削
little kids I mean it's just kind
小孩发财。我的意思是，这感觉有点……
you know I maybe to other people on
你知道，这似乎很明显。也许对其他
chocolate don't care but I the first
巧克力爱好者来说，我不在乎，但我第一次
thing when I heard about it I was like
听到这件事的时候，就想：
why why is this a thing it reminds me of
为什么会有这种事？这让我想起了
somewhat of again of Elon Musk and what
埃隆·马斯克和
his mission was with Tesla he kind of
他创办特斯拉的初衷。他很清楚，
knew that if he was able to prove that
如果他能证明可以
you can have fast um nice electric cars
拥有快速、漂亮的电动汽车，
then the rest of the industry could give
那么其他厂商就无法再用“这
up their excuses that it's not possible
不可能”之类的借口搪塞了。但是，
exactly um what if someone comes along
如果有人跑来说：“
though and they say Okay Jimmy we'll
吉米，我们
give you five billion for feast hell no
给你50亿美元买Feast（指Feast品牌）！” 绝对不行，
I ain't selling that [__] you're never
我才不卖呢，你永远也
selling it no because the first thing
卖不出去。因为
they would do to up the margins is they
他们提高利润的第一件事就是
just dropped ethical sourcing
放弃道德采购。然后就会
you have people come along and offered
有人跑来说……
to buy your YouTube channel uh I mean
要我买你的YouTube频道，嗯，是的，
yeah I've been offered a billion dollars
我收到过十亿美元的报价，
here or crazy amounts of money there but
或者其他数额巨大的报价。但
I mean it's you know what's funny is
你知道，有趣的是，
Zuck got that famous billion dollar
扎克伯格收到过著名的十亿美元收购
offer for Facebook and he said what was
Facebook的报价，他说：“
it he was like why would I sell the
我为什么要卖掉这个
social media platform I would just take
社交媒体平台？我拿着钱
the money and start a new one and I kind
再创建一个新的，而且我挺喜欢我现在的这个平台，
of like the one I have so why don't I
所以为什么不继续做下去呢？”
just keep it and I I every time I get
每次收到报价（虽然
which I haven't in a while but you know
我已经很久没收到过了），
back in the day I used to like jokingly
我都会开玩笑地四处打听，
poke around just to see what people
看看人们
would offer me um and I would get those
会给我开出多少钱。我收到过这些
offers and then I would always just be
报价，然后我总是会想：“是
like yeah I I would just do the same
啊，我还是继续做
thing I'm doing now so I might as well
我现在做的事情吧，所以不如
just keep doing what I'm doing now you
继续做我现在做的事情。” 你
know the money won't really change
知道，钱并不会改变
anything well done and I don't think you
什么。做得好！我觉得
you've yet to get the credit you deserve
你还没有得到应有的认可，因为
for the the lengths you've gone to with
你为
febles no but I think it's really
Febles付出了很多努力。不，但我认为这非常
important I know you're not doing it for
重要。我知道你做这一切根本不是为了
credit at all I know that you're doing
名利。我知道。 你这样做是为了传递
it to get the message out there so that
信息，让
the industry changes but I think someone
行业改变，但我认为像
like you with a platform that you have
你这样拥有平台的人，
that's able to produce chocolate that is
能够生产出如此
[__] delicious they sent me a box of
美味的巧克力——大概六个月前他们寄给我一盒——
I I hate so much the [__] I'm
我非常讨厌它。我正在
thinking of updating yeah I mean if you
考虑更新包装。是的，我的意思是，如果你
hand them to me like hand me a couple
递给我几块
bars the there's uh a lot of stuff that
巧克力，你会发现很多东西……
uh the problem is like if you look at
问题是，如果你
this and this you know from a distance
从远处看，
you can't tell really the difference
你根本分辨不出它们的
between the flavors like this is dark
味道，比如这是黑
sea salt this is just dark chocolate so
海盐味，这是普通的黑巧克力。所以，
uh I'm about to update the wrappers
我打算更新包装，
where we're going to put like colored
我们会在
tips here so you can tell the flavors
这里加上彩色标记，这样你就能从远处分辨出不同的口味了。
from far away uh I think that's very
我认为这非常
important um another thing too that uh I
重要。还有一件事……
a uh you made a mistake you put these in
你犯了个错误，你把这些放在
front of me now I'm the other thing I W
我面前……还有一件事……我一直在
experimenting and the newer renders are
尝试，新的渲染效果
looking good with putting like right
看起来不错，就像放在
here every bite helps uh get kids out of
这里一样。 每一口都能帮助孩子们摆脱
child labor putting that on the front
童工，把这个放在正面，
and then I I'm you know we're messing
然后你知道，我们正在尝试
around with different Machinery I feel
不同的机器。我觉得
like the images of the chocolate on the
正面的巧克力图片
front could be a little higher quality
质量可以再提高一些，
the back is pretty ass um I want to you
背面简直糟透了。我想
know put some more messaging on the back
在背面多加一些信息，有
of it there's a lot that needs to be
很多地方需要改进，比如
like the white tips here it just makes
这里的白色尖端，它让巧克力
it so obvious from far away what this
从远处就能一眼看出是什么
flavor is whereas all these blend in and
口味，而其他部分则融合在一起，
so yeah brutal got to fix it you you
所以，是的，很糟糕，必须改进。你
talked about your friends calling you
提到你的朋友打电话给你，
and asking you for business advice and
向你寻求商业建议，
you helping them Drive their businesses
你帮助他们发展业务，
up but just watching you there pick
但看着你
apart your own business made me think
剖析自己的生意，我想到有
that there's a lot of entrepreneurs that
很多创业者在
watch our show that are early in their
看我们的节目，他们正处于
own businesses and many of them will be
创业初期，其中许多人都会
you're going to fail you're going to
失败，你会
fail a ton I mean when I first started
失败很多次。我的意思是，我刚开始做巧克力的时候，我
how bad I [__] up our original Bars
搞砸得有多惨，真是太搞笑了。我们最初的巧克力棒
were like very thin there's a reason why
很薄，
like chocolate bars have these like
巧克力棒之所以有这些
break points here where they like break
容易断裂的断点是有原因的，
easily I didn't know that um and so mine
我以前不知道这一点。 嗯，我的巧克力
was just one solid sheet of chocolate
盒里只有一整块巧克力，
but that's almost like a piece of glass
但它就像玻璃一样，
whereas if you drop it it just shatters
如果掉在地上就会碎成很多
into like a bunch of little pieces and
小块。
um and I also didn't know that there's a
嗯，我以前也不知道还有
thing called a a package engineer and
包装工程师这种职业。
can you hand me a box of febles uh my
你能给我一盒Febles巧克力吗？嗯，就是我
original chocolate box when you pop
原来的巧克力盒。当你打开盒子，把它放在
these open and put it on a shelf there
架子上时，
this obviously the problem's fixed but
问题就解决了。但
if if this was sitting on a shelf when
如果这个盒子放在架子上，当
you grab this one these would all slide
你拿起这块巧克力时，它们都会
forward and then they would fall out of
向前滑，然后掉出
the box and or the box would fall off
盒子，或者因为盒子底部和边缘的重量不平衡，整个盒子会从架子上掉下来。以前
and the lips here this this didn't used
没有这种设计，所以这些巧克力是
to be a thing so these were open and
敞开的，只有底部的边缘，
there was just a bottom lip here and so
所以
they would fall out like that um and
它们会像这样掉出来。嗯，
then the bars because we didn't have the
然后巧克力棒因为没有
natural break points would shatter like
天然的断裂点，就会像
glass who noticed that um well me and
玻璃一样碎裂。谁注意到这一点的？嗯，是我。
the thing is I I this a old team in
问题是，我以前在
feasts I would tell them like there's
Feasts公司工作，我去沃尔玛的时候会跟他们说，
too many broken bars when I go into
碎掉的巧克力棒太多了。
Walmart I'm seeing too many that are
我看到太多
broken they told me like ah you're
碎巧克力了，他们跟我说，哎呀，你太
worrying about this too much it's not
担心了，这没什么大不了的，
everyone and I got to the point where it
谁都会遇到这种情况。但我实在忍无可忍了，
was just [__] pissing me off because
因为
I hated like grabbing a bar off the
我讨厌从地上捡起巧克力棒，
ground or seeing on the Shelf all these
或者看到货架上全是
like shattered chocolate bars that I I
碎掉的巧克力棒。我甚至花钱请
put like uh I paid people to put GoPros
人把GoPro藏
in like a a like a bag of lace ships
在一袋蕾丝包装袋里对着拍，
pointed at because I couldn't get I
因为我搞不到
tried to get Walmarts to give me the
沃尔玛的监控录像，他们不肯给我。
wouldn't so I put hidden GoPros and a
所以我自己找了好几家沃尔玛，把GoPro藏起来
at the feastival bars just to see why
对着节日巧克力棒拍，想看看
are they [__] breaking so much
它们为什么这么容易碎。有
there's so many shots of like you know
很多镜头，比如
like a mom grabbing a bar and then she'd
一个妈妈拿起一根巧克力棒，她正
be looking at it literally like this and
看着它，然后
then you just see the Box just go and
盒子就掉了，
she' go and they' just fall off the
她也跟着掉了，巧克力棒就这么从
shelf and then they just put it up and
货架上掉下来，然后他们又把巧克力棒放回去，
you you know some of the bars would be
你知道，有些巧克力棒已经
broken and it would just happen over and
碎了，就这么发生了。 一遍又一遍，
over and over again because we didn't
因为我们没把
engineer the boxes correctly they didn't
盒子设计好，它们本身并没有
do anything wrong do you know how a
做错什么。你知道吗？就像
typical that is what you've just said
你刚才说的，
that you put GoPros yeah people told me
你装了GoPro。是啊，很多人都说
I was crazy the amount of people who
我疯了，很多人都说
tried to tell me that was illegal I was
我这么做违法。我
like bro I don't [__] care I just
就想，兄弟，我他妈才不在乎，我
need know why my bars are breaking like
只想知道为什么我的信号杆会断，
I'll delete the footage um and so I that
我可以把录像删掉。嗯，所以我就这么做了。
and uh you know I did a bunch of just
你知道，我做了
fix up the boxes it's pretty expensive I
很多数据收集。我发现有一家叫Aosta的公司，你可以花钱雇人去沃尔玛。于是我开始花钱雇人，每周派人去美国所有的沃尔玛，把所有坏掉的信号杆都买下来，然后把盒子修好。我觉得挺贵的，
think um you know it's like $100,000
嗯，你知道，光是
just to send someone into every single
派人去每个
Walmart to clean them up $28 a pop times
沃尔玛清理一下就要10万美元，每个28美元，5000家
5,000 um uh Walmarts and um yeah so I
沃尔玛。嗯，所以，我
was sending people into Walmart to clean
派人去沃尔玛
up the broken bars and that but I was
清理坏掉的信号杆，就这样。 我
paying so much money it was $100,000 a
花了那么多钱，每周光派人去就得花10万美元，
week just to send people in and then I
然后我还
was buying all these broken bars because
买了一堆碎巧克力棒，因为
I just really didn't want people to go
我真的不想让大家
into Walmart and to buy a broken Feast
去沃尔玛买碎掉的Feast巧克力
bar like that is literally the worst you
棒，这简直是你
know consumer experience you can have um
能体验到的最糟糕的购物体验。嗯，
and yeah and then I learned what a
后来我才知道
package engineer is and I was like holy
包装工程师是干什么的，我当时就想，我的天哪，原来包装
it where my boxes don't [__] fall
盒不倒就是你的全职工作，
over where have you been but on the
你之前都干嘛去了？不过说到
point that I was saying your obsession
我刚才说的，你
with the D of a product is it's
对产品细节的执着
completely atypical and if I was to
完全不寻常。如果拿
compare this to a normal YouTuber and
一个普通的YouTube博主和
their e-commerce brand oh they wouldn't
他们的电商品牌比，他们根本不会
give a [__] yeah I was I probably spent
在意这些。没错，我可能花了
thousands of hours obsessing over this
成千上万个小时来研究这个
product I mean I know it doesn't feel
产品。我知道你可能感觉不到，
like it because it's just chocolate but
因为它只是巧克力而已，但
yeah I mean it's it's a problem from the
确实，从
ethical sourcing to every little thing
道德采购到每一个细节，这都是个问题。我做事从不敷衍了事，
anything half has and didn't you drive
你不是跑了
to a ton of Walmarts don't you oh all
很多家沃尔玛吗？ 你不是吗？哦，
the time that's what I do every day oh
我一直都这么做，我每天都这么做。哦，
[__] we should go hit to Walmart we
该死，我们应该去沃尔玛逛逛，我们
didn't even go ah he's got a plan he's
还没去呢。啊，他有计划，他
got to catch yeah it's my favorite thing
得抓住机会。是啊，我最喜欢
to do is like sometimes I'll spend all
做的事就是，有时候我会
night in Walmart just uh scanning
在沃尔玛待一整晚，就看看
products and looking at the daily
商品，看看每日的
velocities and sales it's it's like uh I
销量和销售额。就像，我之前在华盛顿特区
had a layover in DC I live in North
转机，我住在
Carolina then I was like wait a minute I
北卡罗来纳州，然后我就想，等等，我
could just rent a car and hit like 30
可以租辆车，
Walmarts on the way home and just drive
回家的路上逛30家沃尔玛，然后开车
home and so then I drove home from DC to
回家。于是我就从华盛顿特区开车回
North Carolina and visited every Walmart
北卡罗来纳州，把美国中部东海岸的每一家沃尔玛都逛了一遍，就为了看看
chocolate aisle and see all the
巧克力货架，看看所有的
statistics and things like that I asked
统计数据之类的。我
you earlier on if you struggled [__] I
之前问过你，你是不是觉得很困难。该死，我真
wish we could go visit a Walmart you
希望我们能去逛逛沃尔玛，你
know how fun that would be it's like I
知道那有多好玩吗？我
would love to educate you on the chocol
真想给你讲讲巧克力。
are Walmart still open now oh no they're
沃尔玛现在还开着吗？哦，
not okay we can do it another time I
不，他们关门了。 我们可以改天再说。我
usually what I do is I just bang on the
通常的做法是直接敲门，
door and they let me in of course yeah
他们当然会让我进去。是啊，
but what you just said there I'm I feel
但你刚才说的，我觉得
like I'm getting at something here
我好像说中了什么，
because
因为
99.99999% of entrepreneurs that I know
我认识的99.99999%的创业者，他们
that just have one thing to do just to
只需要做一件事来
run their business don't give that many
经营自己的生意，所以不太在意
[__] about the detail and you have like
细节。而你却有数不清的
a zillion things to do an Amazon show
事情要做，比如亚马逊的节目，这可是
whatever of all time or whatever and you
史上最火的节目之一，你还有
have this massive Channel you have your
个庞大的频道，你做
philanthropy you have all of this stuff
慈善，你还有所有这些事情在做，
going 100 million followers on Tik Tok
TikTok上有1亿粉丝，
gazillion followers here a gazillion
这里也有数不清的粉丝，数不清的粉丝，这些
followers the numbers are just
数字简直
unfathomable and you're still driving to
难以想象。可你还要开车跑
31 Walmarts to check if your chocolate
31家沃尔玛，看看你的巧克力有没有
is breaking yeah well and I go in the
碎。是啊，
back when I'm there if it's not on the
我去的时候还会去仓库后面，如果
shelf and I'll go scan it in and help
货架上没有，我就去扫描入库，帮帮
the employees and and is that is that
员工。这就是
the difference well you just got to know
区别吗？嗯，你必须了解
everything going on it's I mean it's
所有的事情，我的意思是，这都是
just first principles every if like like
最基本的原则。 我最
I I hate when someone in my business is
讨厌的就是，公司里有人跟
like tells me something that I don't
我说一些我不
agree with but I'm too ignorant to be
认同的话，但我又因为无知而无法
able to challenge them because then it's
反驳。那样的话，我就觉得自己算老几？我只能默默接受。
got to just take them on the word but
但
most people tend to pick the easiest
大多数人倾向于选择最简单的
route or conform to the status quo and I
路，或者墨守成规。而
want to if I want to lead real
如果我想引领真正的
Innovation and like change the industry
创新，改变整个行业，
then I got to know every little facet of
我就必须了解所有细节。毕竟，
the day you know the Shelf is where
货架是
people buy it so I got to intricately
人们购买商品的地方，所以我必须深入
know everything going on at the touch
了解
point of the consumer and you know how
消费者接触点的每一个环节，包括商品如何运送到货架，如何
it gets there how it's being stored at
在
the D distribution centers and then the
配送中心储存，如何到达
retailer and then on the shelf and what
零售商，以及在货架上的样子、
experience and everything because all
体验等等。因为所有
these little things add up do you not
这些小细节加起来就至关重要。你是不是
feel like you spend your whole life
觉得你一辈子都在跟
fighting people to raise their standards
别人争论，试图让他们的标准达到
to your standards because you don't
你的标准？因为你生活
exist in a world of Mr beasts well that
在一个没有Mr. Beast的世界里。嗯，
that's the thing I used to think which I
我以前就是这么想的，而且
I've said a couple times it was just
我已经说过好几次了。 一开始只是觉得
content but I realized it's just
满足就好，但我意识到，
everything I do like I just want to be
我做的每件事都是如此，我只想做到
the best at it and that's it's weird man
最好。这很奇怪，
because you just look at this choca bar
因为你看看这块巧克力，
and you wouldn't you'd be like who the
你可能不会在意，你会想谁会在乎它。
[__] cares but that's the thing it's
但关键就在这里，
it's what I've really enjoyed the last
过去两年我真正享受的是，
two years is I've gone as in depth on
我像经营
this as I have YouTube and it's been
YouTube频道一样深入地钻研它，而且
every bit as fun I mean it's very very
乐趣丝毫不减。我的意思是，它真的非常非常
[__] difficult and and hard
难，尤其是
especially the ethical sourcing and like
道德采购方面。比如，
I recently spent a week in West Africa
我最近在西非待了一周，从可可豆到巧克力
to the bar and like you worked on the
棒，我全程参与，在农场工作，
farm and follow the entire QC Supply
追踪整个质量控制供应
Chain and everything and it's not it's
链等等。它和
like it's equally as hard as my YouTube
我的YouTube频道一样难，
channel but it's also equally as fun and
但也一样有趣。这对
opener for me because I never thought I
我来说是一次巨大的启迪，因为我从未想过我
would enjoy something as much as uh my
会像喜欢我的
YouTube channel and that's what I was
YouTube频道一样喜欢其他事情。就像我
saying earlier I've come to realize I
之前说的，我逐渐意识到，我
deeply enjoy building businesses and
非常享受创建企业和
solving hard complex problems even
解决复杂难题的过程。
though I know this is just chocolate but
我知道这只是巧克力，但
I get the complex thing from the ethical
我每天都要处理道德采购方面的复杂问题，比如
that that's fun with beast beast games
Beast Games，还有
with this with all the other things
其他一些事情，比如
going on um your main Channel which is I
你的主频道，我
guess you probably still see as your
想你可能在某种程度上仍然把它看作是你的
baby to some degree it's like the
孩子，就像
Mothership right because it's the source
母舰一样，对吧？因为它是一切的源泉，
of it it's what allows us to do
它让我们能够做
everything like most people buying this
所有的事情。大多数人购买这款产品
aren't buying it because of Beast games
并不是因为Beast Games，
do you ever get paranoia when the views
你会不会在观看量下降时感到焦虑？虽然观看量并
go down they haven't gone down yet
没有下降，
they've gone up every year for 14 years
14年来每年都在增长，
but do you still get that that do you
但你还会感到焦虑吗？你
still watch the video go live and look
还会观看视频直播并查看
at the back end no you don't no I mean
后台数据吗？不会，不会。我的意思是，
because it's like we uh I don't know I
我们
just upload a video and then the next
上传视频后，
day I look at the retention and the CTR
第二天就会查看用户留存率和点击率，
and if we [__] up I just you know well
如果我们搞砸了，
what we do is we call them after action
我们称之为事后
reports so I get all the smartest people
报告。我会让公司里所有最聪明的人来分析，比如
in my company like like uh we like we
我们刚刚就
actually just did one I wish I had my
做了一份，真希望我当时在场。
had it on me but like we'll we I have I
这事儿得我自己来做，不过我们得
pay this guy to just do a very in-depth
付钱请这个人做个非常深入的
breakdown of like here's the retention
分析，比如，这是用户留存率
chart here's every time someone clicked
图表，这是每次用户点击
away here's where was the flattest
离开的时间点，这是留存率最低的地方，这是留存率
here's where was the worst you know
最高的地方。比如说，
we'll take like so if I upload a video
如果我上传一个
that's 20 minutes we'll take our last 10
20分钟的视频，我们会选取最近10个
20 minute videos and we'll go you know
20分钟的视频，然后计算
uh the median retention on the last 10
留存率的中位数。 过去10个
20 minute videos was 10 minutes and 6 or
20分钟的视频，平均观看时长是10分6秒或
55 seconds is the median so if the
55秒。所以，如果
retention on this new video is 11
这个新视频的观看时长达到
minutes or above we did a good job if
或超过11分钟，我们就做得不错；如果
it's below that then we did below
低于11分钟，那就低于
average and blah blah blah and and he
平均水平，等等等等。他就像在做
just does like a a giant like
一场大型
presentation and so usually two weeks
演讲。通常情况下，
after we upload we'll we'll look at that
上传两周后，我们会
with all my top people and then we'll
和所有核心成员一起观看，然后我们会反思：
just be like what' we [__] up what we do
我们哪里搞砸了？好吧，继续
on and has there ever been a moment in
前进。
real recent times where you go I think I
最近有没有哪个时刻，你会觉得“我
need to spend more time on it again and
需要再花更多时间，重新投入进去”？
get back in there and because all the
因为
time you know but a lot of that stems
你知道，这种情况经常发生，但很多时候都源于不
from insecurity I mean cuz the thing is
安全感。我的意思是，
of course we we had a video recently
我们最近发布了一个视频，
every minute someone is eliminated it
每分钟都有人被淘汰，但效果
didn't performed the best um you know
并不理想。你知道，我们的
and their like our intro was a little
开头有点
repetitive it was a little dark it um it
重复，有点阴暗。我们把一些
we had we brought back like losers from
在
Beast games to compete in a main Channel
Beast Games中失败的人召回，让他们参加主频道
video but the problem is some people
视频的比赛，但问题是有些人
thought it was Beast games they like oh
认为…… 他们喜欢的那些精彩游戏，哦，
I've already seen this there was just a
我已经看过了，
lot of rookie mistakes there and it's
里面有很多新手才会犯的错误。
very easy for me to like you know get
我很容易因此感到
insecure and and like be like [__] this
不安，然后想“操，这就是
is why I need to be in the weeds but the
我需要深入细节的原因”，但说到底，就像
when I was calling all the shots I was
我以前发号施令的时候也不是
perfect either so as long as it's like
完美无缺的。所以，只要
as long as when people make mistakes
人们犯错后能从中
they learn from them I have a say like
吸取教训，我就有发言权。我总是这样跟
that I tell people all the time like
别人说，比如
like whenever our new creatives [__] up
我们新来的创意人员搞砸了，我
I I'll look at Tyler I go Tyler's
就会看着Tyler说：“Tyler的
dollars in bad decisions like this isn't
错误决定让我损失了数千万美元，这不会
going to be the first time you [__] us
是你第一次让我们损失
out of a million dollars as long as you
一百万美元，只要你能从中吸取教训就行了。”
learn from it it's fine um and so as
所以，
long as like that's where these after
这些
action reports are are important because
事后报告很重要，因为
as long as we when we mess up we
只要我们犯错后能清楚地
articulate why and it doesn't happen
说明原因，并且不再犯同样的错误，那就没什么问题了。但是，
I mean if the same thing was happening
如果同样的事情
over and over and over again that'd be
一而再、再而三地发生…… 那感觉就像“卧槽，
like [__] I need to get step in but my
我得赶紧插手”，但我的
my guys are just good like they don't
团队很厉害，他们不会
make the same mistake twice tell me
犯同样的错误两次。跟我说说
about experimentation and testing cuz
实验和测试吧，因为
people look to you as the the real king
大家都把你视为真正的
of like testing and experimentation how
实验和测试之王。
Central is this to the success of
这对
everything that you do very much and
你所做的一切的成功有多重要？非常重要。就是这样，比如那个“
that's the thing like that every minute
每分钟都有人淘汰”的
video like it flopped you know and that
视频就失败了。你知道，
was your your highest chance of flopping
失败的几率最高
is when you do something new like really
就是当你做一些全新的东西，非常非常
really new uh one of our bigger flops
全新的东西的时候。嗯，我们
before that too is we did this video
之前也失败过一次，我们做了一个视频，
where it was like 10 minutes this room
大概10分钟后这个房间
will explode we built this giant Tower
会爆炸。我们搭建了一座巨大的塔，
had a guy start at the top he had to
让一个人从塔顶开始，他必须把它炸掉。这是
make it it was a real- time shoot down
一个实时射击，
press a button yeah it was just didn't
按下一个按钮。是的，它的
perform that well people didn't really
效果不太好，人们不太
like it um is kind of complicated blah
喜欢。嗯，有点复杂，等等等等。
blah and it's like you have to be
你必须
careful because you know um I want I
小心，因为你知道，我
want a culture where people feel
想要一种文化，让大家可以
comfortable experimenting and trying and
自在地进行实验和尝试，并且不介意
feel fine failing and so you know when
失败。所以你知道，当
that video failed or when you know that
那个视频失败的时候，或者当你知道“
every minute this someone's eliminated
每分钟都有人被淘汰”的时候……
like you know I don't go and yell at
你知道我不会对
people or call them idiots or anything
人大吼大叫，也不会骂他们是白痴什么的，
like that I just I'm like what did we do
我只会问他们“我们
wrong all right here's all the facts
做错了什么？”，然后把所有事实都摆出来，
just make sure it doesn't happen again
确保以后不会再发生这种事。这也不是
not going to be the first time you cost
你们第一次让
me a bunch of money it's all good you
我损失一大笔钱了，没关系。你
know I see this as investing in you guys
知道，我把这看作是对你们的投资，
and let's just learn from it I was gonna
让我们从中吸取教训。我本来
say because um or else if if there was a
想说，否则，如果这种风气盛行，
culture of that then people would just
人们就会一遍又一遍地
make the same videos again and a lot of
制作同样的视频，很多
YouTubers just ch out the same format
YouTuber也只是重复同样的模式。
I'm okay with my people failing I'm okay
我可以接受我的团队失败，我可以
with the video being 10 out of 10 like
接受视频是满分10分，
as long as we actually took an honest
只要我们真的认真地
good um try at it you know and and as
尝试过了，
long as we failed because we made the
只要我们失败是因为我们做出了
wrong shot call not because we were lazy
错误的决定，而不是因为我们懒惰，或者
not because we didn't put the effort in
因为我们没有付出努力等等，
ETC as long as if as long as it's just
只要
like we made an educated decision to
我们只是经过深思熟虑后决定去
test something or try something and it
测试或尝试一些东西，而结果却失败了，
just didn't work I'm cool with that we
我就能接受。我们
can do that all day and like they know
可以一直这样做，就像他们一样。 我知道
that and i' I don't yell at people um
这一点，而且我不会对别人大吼大叫，也不会因为
you know or get mad at them when they um
他们不小心犯错而生气。
accidentally mess up like that I've
我
invested more than a million pounds into
在Perfect Ted这家公司投资了超过一百万英镑，
this company Perfect Ted and they're
他们
also a sponsor of this podcast I
也是这个播客的赞助商。我已经
switched over to using matcher as my
改用抹茶作为我的
dominant energy source and that's where
主要能量来源，而
perfect Ted comes in they have the match
Perfect Ted正是我需要的。他们有抹茶粉、
powders they have the match drinks they
抹茶饮​​料、抹茶
have the pods and all of this keeps me
胶囊等等，所有这些都能让我即使在
focused throughout a very very long
漫长的
recording day no matter what's going on
录音日里也能保持专注，无论发生什么。
and their team is obsessed with quality
他们的团队对品质极其执着，所以
which is why they Source their
他们
ceremonial grade matcha from Japan so
从日本采购仪式级抹茶。因此，
when people say to me that they don't
当人们告诉我他们不
like the taste of matcha I'm guessing
喜欢抹茶的味道时，我猜
that they haven't tried perfect Ted
他们还没试过Perfect Ted。
unlike lowquality matcha that has a
不像那些劣质抹茶有
bitter grassy taste perfect Ted is
苦涩的草味，Perfect Ted口感
smooth and naturally sweet and without
顺滑，天然甘甜。
head customer already if you're getting
如果你在像
your match at places like blank Street
Blank Street
or Joe and the juice but now you can
或Joe and the Juice这样的地方买抹茶，你可能已经是Perfect Ted的忠实客户了。现在你可以
make it yourself at home so give it a
在家自己制作了，所以不妨
try and we'll see if you still don't
试试看，看看你是否还会喜欢。 不
like matcha so here what I'm going to do
喜欢抹茶？没关系！
matcher if you try it today head to
今天就来试试我们的抹茶机，享受40%的折扣！访问
perfect ted.com and use code
perfect ted.com，使用优惠码
st40 or if you're in a supermarket you
st40即可。或者，如果你在超市，
can get it at tesos or Holland and
可以在Tesos或Holland &amp;
Barett or in the Netherlands at Albert
Barrett购买；在荷兰，可以在Albert
Heine and those of you in the US you can
Heine购买；在美国，可以
get it on Amazon as you guys know whoop
在亚马逊购买。大家都知道，Whoop
is one of my show sponsors it's also a
是我的节目赞助商之一，也是
company that I have invested in and it's
我投资的公司。你们经常
one that you guys asked me about a lot
问我关于Whoop的问题，其中最常被问到的就是
the biggest question I get asked is why
为什么选择
use whoop over other wearable technology
Whoop而不是其他可穿戴设备。
options and there is a bunch of reasons
原因有很多，
but I think it really comes down down to
但我认为最关键的一点是
it's noninvasive nature when everything
它最容易被忽视却又至关重要的特性：无干扰性。当
in life seems to be competing for my
生活中所有的事情都在争夺我的
attention I turn to whoop because it
注意力时，我会选择Whoop，因为它
doesn't have a screen and will armed the
没有屏幕。Whoop的
CEO who came on this podcast told me the
CEO也来参加过这个播客节目，他告诉我，Whoop
reason that there's no screen because
没有屏幕的原因是屏幕会
screens equal distraction so when I'm in
分散注意力。所以，当我在
meetings or I'm at the gym my whoop
开会或在健身房时，我的Whoop
doesn't demand my attention it's there
不会打扰我。 我的注意力一直都在
in the background constantly pulling
后台，不断地
data and insights from my body that are
从我的身体中提取数据和见解，以便在
ready for when I need them if you've
我需要时随时可用。如果你一直在
been thinking about joining whoop you
考虑加入 Whoop，你
can head to join. woop.com
可以前往加入。 加入 whoop.com，即可
CEO and try whoop for 30 days risk-free
免费试用 whoop 30 天，
and zero commitment that's join.
无需承担任何风险和义务。
woop.com
woop.com 的
CEO let me know how you get on you've
CEO，让我知道你今天过得怎么样。你
just concluded today the biggest
刚刚结束了
competition show I think of all time
我认为有史以来规模最大的竞赛节目，
history most camera yeah and what 50
嗯，的确是有史以来规模最大的。但我想你们创造了 50 项吉尼斯世界纪录，你知道，史上最大的布景、史上最多的世界纪录、史上最高的奖金、史上最多的获胜者、史上最多的参赛者、史上最多的摄像机。是的，还有 50 项
Guinness World Records yeah that we know
吉尼斯世界纪录，是的，我们知道的，
of there's probably way more but yeah
可能还有更多。
you said something on stage which I
你在台上说的一句话我
found quite interesting you said I kind
觉得很有意思，你说你有点
of feel a bit sad yeah I know because
难过。是的，我知道，因为
every Thursday I got to look forward to
每个星期四我都期待着
like seeing the internet's reaction to
看到互联网对《
Beast games and now I'm gonna wake up
野兽游戏》的反应，而现在
next Thursday and I don't I don't get to
下周四早上醒来，我就看不到
see what people think it's over they
大家对节目的看法了。他们把
they describe um this in the Olympics as
奥运会上的这种情况称为“
gold medal depression really yeah they
金牌抑郁症”。真的吗？是的，他们
say I think it's I might butcher these
说，我想是这样的，我可能记错了，
numbers but 70% of people after the
但 70% 的人在奥运会后，
Olympics even if they won a gold medal
即使他们赢得了金牌，也会
mhm experience depression afterwards
经历抑郁症，
because they they' lost their North Star
因为他们失去了
that was giving them meaning in yeah no
赋予他们意义的北极星。是的，不，
I mean I'm not I I mean I I guess I'm
我的意思是，我不是…… 我的意思是，我猜我有点
playfully sad but I don't it's fine we
装可怜，但其实没关系，我们只是……我手头有
just I got I have so much [__] going on
太多破事儿要忙，根本
I don't even really get to think about
没时间想这些，
that kind of stuff and you're on to the
而你们又在忙下
next one uh yeah so we'll well Amazon
一个了。嗯，是的，所以，亚马逊，我们赶紧把
let's get season two in the books
第二季敲定吧，快点
already come on let's sign a contract
签合同。现在还
can't really talk about it is the most
不能多说，这是
me and Jack were talking about earlier
我和杰克之前聊到的，
on it is the most incredible thing that
这绝对是
I think I've seen on TV and I just think
我在电视上见过的最不可思议的东西。我就是觉得，我
the other day
前几天在电话里跟你说过，我看着
I watch it knowing that unless you do
它，心里想着，除非你们再做
another one I will never see something
一季，否则我再也看不到
on this magnitude and scale no one wants
这种规模的节目了。没人
to do something like I mean because it's
想做这种事，因为这真的
[__] hard man and those sets and the
太难了，那些布景……
the thing is the reason why a lot of
关键是，很多
reality TV doesn't feel that way uh and
真人秀节目给人的感觉都不一样。嗯，
we could have obviously done much better
我们当然可以把
storytelling and we will when we do
故事讲得更好，
future iterations but the the at its
以后的几季我们会改进的。但关键在于，
Crux like what people don't see is like
人们看不到的是，
to have a thousand cameras recording the
要用上千台摄像机记录下我们搭建的
amount of infrastruct like we broke a
基础设施，我们简直要崩溃了。 创造了一项
world record for most camera cables ran
世界纪录，用了最多的摄像机线缆，
like the like the most miles of camera
比如说，用了最长的
cables and
线缆，
like and the millions of dollars we had
还有数百万美元的
to spend on storage and millions of
存储设备，数百万
dollars on the control room and the
美元的控制室，以及数百万
millions upon millions of dollars of
美元的剪辑
Hardware to edit it and like having to
硬件，甚至还要
bring in Adobe to custom change the
请Adobe来定制修改
Adobe software where you could actually
软件，才能
have that many multi cams it's like it
支持这么多多机位拍摄。要
actually be able to do that is
实现这一切，实际的基础设施
incredibly incredibly difficult and um
极其复杂。所以
that's why usually what they'll do is
通常情况下，他们会说：“好了，
they'll be like all right here's a 1H
这里有一个小时的时间，
hour like if you're filming a reality
比如如果你在拍摄真人秀，
show here's a 1 hour window you know
这里有一个小时的拍摄窗口。”
they'll send out story producers they'll
他们会派出故事策划，
put a camera on you they'll be like yo
把摄像机对着你，然后问：“嘿，你
can you say this line you're kind of our
能说这句台词吗？你扮演的是
villain this is what we're looking for
反派，这就是我们想要的。”
they'll kind of tell you what to say and
他们会告诉你该说什么，
then they'll write the notes down and
然后把笔记记下来，
they'll catalog it for the editors
整理好交给剪辑师。而
whereas we're just like [__] it we're
我们呢，就直接说：“管他呢，我们要
going to be filming you know 24/7 all
24小时不间断拍摄，
these cameras you guys be yourselves
这么多摄像机，你们就等着吧。” 你们自己来
we'll just capture it because you don't
录吧，因为你不
know when someone's going to do
知道什么时候会有人做出什么
something weird you don't know when
奇怪的举动，也不知道什么时候会
someone's going to whisper to someone in
有人私下跟别人
form an alliance you don't know so you
结盟，什么都不知道，所以你们只能
literally have to just be rolling and
随机应变，而且需要拍摄
you need these to be acceptable angles
角度合适的素材，
so you need multiple an a cam and a b
所以需要多个A机位、B
Cam and all this which creates a
机位等等，这会产生海量的素材。
Monumental fuckload of footage but
但
that's what allowed us that was I mean
正是这些素材让我们得以拍摄，我的意思是，
when filming Beast games is we put in
在拍摄Beast Games时，我们最大的竞争优势之一就是我们投入
the effort to to set up all this
精力搭建了所有这些
infrastructure we could actually capture
基础设施，这样我们才能真正捕捉到画面，
it and just tell the story how it is
并如实讲述故事，而不是让
instead of having to use story producers
编剧替人
to put words in people's mouths but it's
编造台词。但这简直是一场
a [__] nightmare man like I had over
噩梦，我当时有超过
150 people editing that I mean we're
150个人在剪辑，我的意思是，我们要
coming through unfathomable amounts of
处理海量的
footage and and everything and I mean
素材，而且所有素材都堆积如山，
even things from like the uh computer
甚至连电脑
network and our local it constantly
网络和本地服务器都经常
crashing because there's just so much
崩溃，因为
footage there and like if I were to send
素材实在太多了。如果我把
all the Beast games footage to just one
所有素材都发过去，那简直太可怕了。 如果把《野兽游戏》的素材交给一个
editor it would probably be like
剪辑师，光硬盘就可能要
$300,000 in hard drives and you know and
30万美元。你知道，
if you have 150 editors it's just
如果有150个剪辑师，那就根本
impossible so we you spend millions of
不可能了。所以我们花了数百万
dollars and you build a central uh
美元建了一个中央
server room and so we have our own
服务器机房，我们有自己的
server acts and everything and then you
服务器，所有设备都
have them remote in there but even then
在那里，然后让他们远程操作。但即便如此，
just due to the sheer volume of footage
由于素材量巨大，
Adobe and everything was constantly
Adobe之类的软件还是经常
crashing and it's like it was it was a
崩溃，
nightmare on the back end but it's great
后台简直是一场噩梦。不过也挺好的，
because that's why we were able to tell
因为正因如此，我们才能把事情的真相还原出来，让观众
what actually happened why it feels
感觉不
different because we were recording
一样。因为我们
non-stop 247 I was wondering as I was
24小时不间断地录制。我一边
watching it if Amazon are aware of the
看一边想，亚马逊是不是知道
the fact that you're just going to give
你们会像这样白白送钱？就像
away the money like this like when you
你们拍《
like flip the queen and it adds another
翻转女王》那样，又赚了
$5 million that didn't affect them I
500万美元，但这对他们来说毫无影响。我
lost a ton of money filming the show so
拍这节目赔了不少钱，都是我自己
that that came out of my pocket because
掏腰包的，因为
really yeah we were we spent way too
真的，我们在这节目上花了
much money on it I lost tens of millions
太多钱，我在这节目上亏了数千万
of dollars on that show really yeah I'm
美元。真的，我…… 真是个
an idiot because the lines came out it
白痴，因为台词出来之后，
was like Amazon give Mr Beast 100
就像亚马逊给了Mr Beast一
million to do yeah show so I'm thinking
亿美元让他做节目一样，所以我就想，
okay I'm doing the math I'm thinking
好吧，我算算，
okay so he spent 20 odd million on the
好吧，他花了2000多万美元在
prizes MH yeah we gave away so there
奖品上，MH，是的，我们送出去了，所以
must be 80 million left or something I
应该还剩下8000万美元左右吧。我的
mean so episode one we spent over $15
意思是，第一集，我们花了超过1500
million on those Towers building them
万美元建那些塔，那
all like that was the most towers ever
是有史以来建造的塔最多的一次，用到的
built the most hydraulic press or
液压机之类的东西也最多。
whatever used I mean that that set was
我的意思是，那套布景简直
[__] crazy man we had to build a
太疯狂了，我们得建
th000 towers that were 10 ft tall safety
1000座10英尺高的塔，还要对它们进行安全
test them all put like get it where they
测试，确保它们能正常
actually work we had to literally
工作。我们得把
hardwire them all and build like our own
它们全部硬连接起来，还要开发我们自己的
software where we could drop people we
软件，让演员可以从上面掉下来。我们
had to put up all the screens I mean
还得安装所有的屏幕。我的意思是，
that was that that was that's like
那可以说是
built in history that was just episode
历史上建造过的最大的布景之一，那只是第一集，
one and that's just like the
而且那还只是
construction of the set That's not
布景的搭建。这还不
including like you said we we gave away
包括，就像你说的，我们送出了
over $20 million I think over two
超过2000万美元，我想第一集就花了超过200
million was in episode one and then
万美元，然后是
episode two we have the city which that
第二集。 第二，我们建了一座城市，那可是花了
was a 14 million dollar set build and
1400万美元搭建的布景，规模非常
that was um huge I mean because that was
庞大，因为那是一座
a real City that they were living in you
他们生活的真实城市。
know um and then I could yeah go but
然后，我可以继续说下去，光是那
just between the 20 whatever two million
两千万美元的
we gave away plus those two sets I mean
赠款加上那两个布景，加起来可能就
you're at over $50 million how much did
超过5000万美元了。整个项目到底花了多少钱？有人
advised not to say because because
建议我不要说，因为
people will hear big number and be like
人们一听到大数字就会想，
oh well I could have made a good show if
哦，如果我有那么多钱，我也能拍出一部好剧。
I had that kind of money but the thing
但问题
is they couldn't because it's if money
是，他们做不到，因为钱
isn't everything like building and
并不是万能的，搭建和
managing it is is you know infinitely
管理一部剧要难得
harder but is it more than 100 million
多。超过1亿美元吗？当然，当然。
well I just told you how we spent 50
我刚才说了我们花了5000万美元，
million and that we're only two episodes
而我们才拍了两集，
in so how out of pocket are you tens of
所以你亏了多少钱？几千万美元。是的，
financial decision to make Beast games I
拍《野兽游戏》并不是一个明智的财务决定，我
lost money I would have more money if I
赔了钱。如果我不拍这部剧，我会赚更多钱。
didn't film it any regrets no no it's
后悔吗？不，不，这
great I mean for for me I was it was
很棒。对我来说…… 当时的目标是尽我所能把第一季
about making season one as good as
做好。
possible you know I can't let the
你知道，我不能让
YouTube Community down because that you
YouTube社区失望，因为你
know creators don't have a good rep when
知道，创作者
it comes to doing stuff on streaming
在流媒体
platforms and you know I'm getting 200
平台上的名声并不好。你知道，我在第一年
million views of video on average over
平均每个视频的播放量都达到了2亿。
the course of the first year and I'm
我
going to talk to these stream platforms
去和这些流媒体平台谈，
and they're like H we've been burned by
他们却说：“我们
creators before I'm like bro I'm not a
以前被创作者坑过。” 我心想，兄弟，我又不是那种只会
Tik tocker that dances I have a
跳舞的TikTok网红，我有自己的
production company and I routinely make
制作公司，我经常制作精彩的
spectacles and even me these streaming
节目。即便如此，这些流媒体
platforms they weren't taking serious so
平台还是不把我当回事。
I was like [__] like if I fail it's over
我当时就想，完了，如果我失败了，一切就都结束了，再也
like no one's ever no streaming platform
没有哪个流媒体平台
is ever going to touch a YouTuber ever
会愿意和YouTube博主合作了。
again so my big thing was just making
所以我当时最重要的是
sure this crushed and you know now the
确保这次合作成功。现在机会来了，
doors are opening up I mean I'm getting
我接到了很多
calls from creators left and right and
创作者的电话，
they're like Oho yeah streaming
他们都说：“哇哦，流媒体
platforms they wouldn't talk to me
平台
before now they're coming like I would
以前根本不理我，现在他们主动
tried to get a meeting with them and
联系我了。我以前想和他们见面，他们总是拒绝，
they were like no now they're like
现在他们真的来了。” 就像
begging to like have meetings with them
恳求和他们见面一样，
and I already know of two creators that
而且我已经知道有两个创作者
have signed deals um just on the backend
签了约，嗯，就凭
success of Beast games and probably I
Beast Games的成功，可能我的
mean hundreds of hundreds of millions of
意思是，明年会有数亿
dollars is going to flow into Creator's
美元的收入流入创作者的
Pockets just because of Beast games in
口袋，就因为Beast Games。
critic to no you you got it was like 90%
你知道，烂番茄可不是个容易评判的影评网站，它居然获得了90%的
approval from fans which is pretty
粉丝好评，这
unheard of in Rotten Tomatoes I know um
在烂番茄上可是闻所未闻的。
but also I hear through the the grape
而且我还听说，
it is on track to become one of Amazon's
它有望成为亚马逊有史以来
biggest shows of all time yeah see the
最火的节目之一。
problem is I have to wait for them to do
问题是，我得等他们发布
a press release so okay yeah well I'm
新闻稿。好吧，
I'm just
我只是
talking I got you I told him I'd be a
随便说说，我明白了。我跟他说过我会
good boy and not leak things so but for
乖乖的，不泄露消息。但是，作为
a a YouTuber quote unquote YouTuber yeah
一个所谓的“油管博主”，嗯，
well they did release it it was their
他们确实发布了，这是他们有史以来收视率最高的
number one unscripted show of all time
真人秀节目。
and then yeah I mean the it's I I don't
然后，嗯，我的意思是，我
think they'd mind me saying it's very
想他们不会介意我说这个
the show's very Evergreen like usually
节目非常非常火。 像
these shows get a lot of attention then
这种常青剧，通常都会获得很多关注，然后就慢慢
kind of like Teeter off but ours is like
淡出人们的视线，但我们的剧
watching it every single day like which
每天都有超过70万的新独立观众观看，这简直太
is pretty crazy because if we maintain
疯狂了。如果我们能保持这个势头，
that like yeah it's going to shatter
它肯定会打破
some pretty crazy records and what's the
一些惊人的记录。
now that it's done because I put all
既然剧已经完结了，你继续宣传它有什么好处呢？因为我投入了
this effort in I want people to see it
这么多精力，我希望大家都能看到它。是的，
promotion I'm doing now I'm not getting
我现在做的所有宣传都没有
paid for really but I mean but I mean I
报酬，真的没有。但我的意思是，好处就是第一季做得
guess the upside would be the better
越好，我第二季、第三季、
I get for season two three four five Etc
第四季、第五季等等就能赚到更多钱。
if I sit here with you in 10 years time
如果十年后我和你坐在这里，
Jimmy yep oh Bo and everything went to
吉米，是的，哦，博，一切都按
plan um you're 36 at that age I already
计划进行。嗯，你那时候36岁了，我
know what you're gonna ask yeah I mean I
知道你会问什么。是的，我
hate that kind of stuff because if you
讨厌这种问题，因为如果你
ask me the problem is if you asked me
问我，问题是，如果你
this like five years ago I never would
五年前问我这个问题，我绝对不会
have said anything about febles or a lot
提到《Febles》或者其他很多
of the stuff I'm doing now and so the
东西。 我现在正在做这件事，所以
honest answer is I don't know I mean I
老实说，我不知道。我的意思是，我
think in what I'm doing you know
觉得就我目前所做的事情而言，你知道，
hopefully by then I have two billion
希望到那时我的YouTube频道能有20亿
subscribers on YouTube you know Beast
订阅者，你知道，Beast
games is bigger than we ever imagine
Games的规模比我们想象的还要大，
hopefully feastival has gotten over a
希望到那时Feastival已经让超过一百
million kids out of child labor by then
万名儿童摆脱了童工的困境。
um and you know I probably will have two
嗯，你知道，我可能还会有两
or three other businesses that I'm very
三个我非常
passionate about that are hopefully
热衷的其他生意，希望它们都能大获成功。是的，我真的
and yeah just I don't know and
不知道。就我
personally maybe I'll have a kid by then
个人而言，也许到那时我会有孩子，
I don't know I mean only time will tell
我不知道，我的意思是，只有时间才能证明一切，
it's it won't be until I feel like I
直到我觉得我有
could actually have enough time to be a
足够的时间做一个
good dad but I I don't even know man I
好爸爸。但是，我真的不知道，伙计，我
don't think about my personal life I
不会去想我的个人生活，我
just think about winning and got to
只想着如何赢得比赛。
build some photos I found that I loved
我找到了一些我喜欢的照片，哦，我的
okay holy [__] is this me or my brother
天哪，这是我还是我兄弟？
me this one as well where did you get
这张也是。你是从哪里找到
these um internet these are on the
这些照片的？嗯，互联网。这些照片都在
internet these are like the really
网上，它们是
iconic photos that I from see really I
我见过的非常经典的照片。真的，我
don't think I've ever seen this one
想我以前从未见过这张。是的，
really yeah I don't do you recognize
你认不出
anything in that photo other than no I
照片里的任何人。 不，我
don't I was just thinking like what
不知道。我只是在想
house am I even in I might be at a
我到底在哪栋房子里。我可能在某个
military base potentially cuz when we
军事基地，因为我们
were younger my both my parents are in
小时候，我父母都在
the military so they're traveling a lot
军队服役，所以他们经常出差。
so this might just be like some random
所以这可能只是个陌生的
house interesting I do recognize this
房子。有意思，我认出这张
like this photo in the background I'm
照片了，背景里这张照片，我
sure you're throw up on screen I think
确定你屏幕上显示的就是它。我想那是，对，就在
hallway beside her bathroom I haven't
她浴室旁边的走廊上。我已经
been to my mom's house in so long um
很久没回我妈妈家了。嗯，你真
interesting you you do so much for
有意思。你为孩子们做了很多事，
children but if you could whisper in
但如果你能悄悄跟
that child's ear something about buy
那个孩子说说买
Bitcoin what was it like two pennies
比特币的事，当时比特币是多少钱来着？好像是两美分？
back then no um I know because I
不，嗯，我知道，因为我
wouldn't want I wouldn't say anything if
不想，就算
you gave me a microphone to talk to him
你给我麦克风跟他说话，我也不会说。
because the problem is I'd be I'd be
因为问题是，我会
worried that it would change you know
担心这会改变我最终的
the outcome of of how I became and like
结局。
I'm very even though I know earlier on I
我知道，虽然之前我
was probably sounded a little depressed
可能听起来有点沮丧，
because shit's hard but you know I'm I
因为生活很艰难，但我很
am happy with the position I am in and I
满意我现在的处境。我
would be worried that you know like this
会担心…… 这
is definitely a very confused child
孩子肯定很迷茫，
that's not fitting in that feels like a
格格不入，觉得自己像个
[__] freak not this young one I don't
怪胎。不是这个小家伙，我不
know what the [__] he's thinking but
知道他脑子里在想什么，但
this one right here probably is around
这个孩子大概和我小时候差不多大，那时候
the age where I was like [__] I'm just a
我就觉得“操，我就是个
[__] weirdo I don't fit in with
怪胎，跟谁都合不来，
anyone why does no one want to build
为什么没人想
businesses and succeed but I think going
创业成功？”但我认为
through that Journey was was important
经历那段旅程很重要，
and it's uh yeah it just gives me a lot
它让我对很多
of conviction with things so I probably
事情都充满信心。所以，如果
if I wasn't allowed to say buy Bitcoin I
我不能说“买比特币”，我可能
just wouldn't say anything what about
什么都不会说。至于
Taha yeah to my
塔哈，是的，对我
mom I would I mean this well what's
妈我会说的。我的意思是，
funny is these are these are two
有趣的是，这两张
different photos of my mom you have like
照片是我妈的不同
this version of my mom I don't think
版本。你看，这是她现在的样子，我觉得我没什么好说的。
I mean cuz she's she was in the military
因为她当过兵，
and they just beat
他们把各种
like systems and order into your head
制度和秩序灌输到你脑子里。
and she this is probably right around
这张照片大概是在
the time where we lost everything and so
我们失去一切的时候拍的，
this you know and she's at a very low
你知道，她当时正处于
point in her life and so I don't think
人生的低谷。所以我觉得
there's anything I could say that ever
我没什么好说的。 说真的，我当时怎么可能说服
would have like convinced her that her
她，让她相信她那个
lunatic son is heading down the right
疯儿子正在走上正轨呢？
path and um you know but you know you
你知道，但你看，这张照片里的
can see the difference here where it's
变化
it's almost indicative where she's
几乎说明了一切，她
smiling in this photo this is when I
在照片里笑得很开心。这是我
gave her 100 Grand this is after we made
给她10万美元的时候拍的，这是我们成功之后拍的，也是在
it this is after we had the whole
我们好好
conversation where she finally is like
谈过之后拍的，她终于说“
okay I'll Trust you you know there's a
好吧，我相信你”。你知道，
these two photos was a very hard journey
这两张照片之间隔了12、13年，那是一段非常艰难的旅程，
um especially when I stopped going to
尤其是我
college and I got straight zeros and I
辍学后，成绩全是零分。我的
mean she thought oh his life's [__]
意思是，她当时想，哦，他的人生完了，
over I just wasted 18 years of my life
我浪费了18年的生命。所以，
you know um so same thing I don't I
同样的事情，
don't I don't think there's anything I
我不认为我
could say that would have changed
说什么能改变
anything um if anything it would have
什么，如果真有什么改变的话，只会
just gave her a heart attack do she do
让她心脏病发作。
you tell her now what she means to you
你现在会告诉她她对你有多重要吗？哦，当然会，她现在
she's very happy and like yeah we're
非常开心，她说：“是的，
we're in a really good spot now I I love
我们现在关系很好，我爱我的……”
my mom I mean because obviously I
妈妈，我的意思是，很明显，
wouldn't be here without her you know
没有她我就不会在这里，你知道
what I mean if she didn't work multiple
我的意思吗？如果她没有同时打好几份
jobs and do all the things she did to
工，没有做那么多事来把我培养成现在的样子，我甚至会做一些小事，比如
things like you know she uh would give
她会给
me like some months like you know 20 $30
我一些零花钱，比如20美元、30美元，
and then I would take that money and use
然后我就用这些钱买
that to like buy stuff to like help make
东西，比如帮我做
videos or or whatever um and even just
视频什么的。还有，
the fact that we had internet you know
我们家能上网，你知道
what I mean and things like that which
我的意思吗？诸如此类的事情，
you know I mean pretty basic now it
你知道，现在这些都很基本，但在当时
wasn't as common back then you used to
并不常见。你
get a phone call and you're like house
接到一个电话，就会说“家里有
internet I don't know if you would go
网络了”，我不知道你是不是会
out yeah and so like you know um it
出门。所以，你知道，当时的
wasn't the best position but she gave me
情况并不好，但她给了我
all the tools I needed to succeed not
成功所需的一切。她不是
you know on purpose but she must be so
故意的，但她肯定很
shocked well she's used to it now but
惊讶，不过她现在已经习惯了。是的，
yeah I mean on the come up I mean it was
我的意思是，在我刚起步的时候，是的，是的，我的
yeah I mean imagine being her you know
意思是，想象一下她，你知道我的
what I mean she used to when I turned 16
意思吗？我16岁的时候，
like she couldn't afford to buy me a car
她甚至买不起车给我，
she couldn't she couldn't afford like
她买不起。 就像
the minivan we had like it was [__]
我们以前那辆破面包车，简直烂透了，
piece of [__] like needed a repair she
需要修理，她根本
couldn't afford it like smoke was coming
负担不起，车头都冒烟了。
out the front of it she was a an
她当时真是
absolute mess and then she comes home
狼狈不堪。然后她回家，
and I'm just like I'm making YouTube
我就跟她说：“我做YouTube
videos [__] math homework mom and you
视频，去他妈的数学作业，妈！”你
know and she's just like she I think she
知道的，然后她说她
was making $40,000 a year cuz I uh we
一年能挣4万美元，因为
didn't talk about Fin is much when we
我们小时候很少谈钱，
were younger but I remember I got a
但我记得我当时签了个
$40,000 brand deal and then she told me
4万美元的品牌代言，然后她告诉我这就是她
that's how much I make in a year and I
一年的收入，我当时就震惊了，心想：我的
was like holy [__] I didn't at the time
天哪！我当时
I was like I thought you made way more
以为你
than 40 Grand a year um and then I was
一年挣的远不止4万美元。然后我就问她：“
like why the [__] are you working like
你干嘛还要工作？
I'm getting paid this per video now on
我现在靠品牌代言，一个视频就能挣这么多钱！”
brand deals and so um
所以，
yeah what an incredible woman I know
嗯，她真是个了不起的女人。我知道她经历了那么多，
to know she she just needs to be happy I
她只需要快乐就好。我
try not to stress her out she's been
尽量不给她压力，她已经
through enough stress like her her job
承受了太多压力，她的工作……
is i' I've been making her not make I
我一直让她别那么辛苦。 我的
mean she wants to do it but like
意思是，她想这么做，比如
exercise routinely do all the like
定期锻炼，做各种
system like body Health scans and you
健康检查，补充
know get on the vitamin grind and
维生素
everything because like I'm not having
什么的，因为我
kids anytime soon but obviously when I
暂时没有要孩子的打算，但很显然，如果我
do have kids I really want her to be
有了孩子，我真的希望她能
involved and she needs to be able to
参与其中，她需要能够和孩子们一起
play with them and things like that so
玩耍之类的。所以
I'm like you know stress is going to
我就跟她说，你知道，压力会要了
kill you you're not allowed to be
你的命，你不能有
stressed you need to do all these Health
压力，你需要遵守所有这些健康
protocols you need to be like cuz you
规程，你需要保持健康，因为你
know you might be in your 70s when I
知道，等我有了孩子，你可能都70多岁了，
have kids like you need to be able to
你需要能够
move around which means you might
四处走动，这意味着
potentially be 80 when they're like 14
当他们14、15岁的时候，你可能都80岁了。拜托，
or 15 like come on like what you do now
你现在的生活方式预示着
you'll be able to be in my kids lives so
你将来能多积极地参与到孩子们的生活中。所以
like and we do the have these
我们会用
conversations in a playful way so she's
轻松的方式谈论这些，她
taking her health very serious for the
非常重视自己的健康，为了
future you're not a man that seems to
未来。你好像不是一个
have many fears but that appears to be
有很多恐惧的人，但这似乎是
one of them a fear that we both share
我们共同的恐惧之一。是的，没错，
yeah exactly I mean hope she'll just
我的意思是，我希望她永远
never die my mom's gonna live forever
不会去世。 妈妈会永远活下去，
we'll be fine Brian
我们会没事的，布莱恩·
Johnson we have a closing tradition on
约翰逊。我们这个播客有个结尾的传统，上一位
this podcast with the last guest Le a
嘉宾会给下一位
question for the next guest not knowing
嘉宾提一个问题，但不知道问题会
who they're leaving it for okay do do I
留给谁。好吧，是我
get hit with the question first or you
先被问到问题，还是你先
get hit with the question first
被问到问题？
okay would you rather die with a sound
你宁愿拥有健全的
body or a sound mind sound body or sound
身体还是健全的头脑？健全的身体还是健全的
mind oh I assume if I chose body then
头脑？哦，我想如果我选择身体，
like that would be like Dementia or
那可能意味着患有痴呆症之类的精神疾病。
something on the mind um that's hard die
嗯，这很难说。是失去身体还是失去头脑？
mind I mean what are you if you don't
我的意思是，如果你失去了头脑，你还算什么？说实话，
have your mind I would say mine to be
我会选择头脑。
honest amen yeah Jimmy thank you do I
阿门。好的，吉米，谢谢你。
get to write my question now you do I
现在轮到我写问题了。轮到你了。
want to say something to you though um I
不过，我想对你说几句。嗯，我
have to give you a lot of credit because
必须非常感激你，因为像我们这样的
so many people like us like our teams we
很多人，像我们的团队，都从
have stolen so much from you we've
你那里学到了很多东西，我们借鉴了
stolen your principles your mentality
你的原则和思维方式，
and it's made us be better creators
这让我们成为了更好的创作者，也让我们能够过上现在的
which has allowed us to live the lives
生活，
that we get to live and do these things
做我们
that we we love the most and um there's
最热爱的事情。嗯，
always a cost I think to being different
我认为与众不同、特立独行总是要付出代价的。 好处当然有，
and to being weird there's an upside but
但
cost and you you pay that cost the most
代价也真的非常非常大，而且
when you're younger and you have to fit
你年轻的时候付出的代价最大，因为你不得不
into the the system and you don't get to
适应这个体制，你没法
choose who you hang around with and
选择和谁交往
stuff um but then as an adult as you
等等。嗯，但就像你
said we all then clap for this the
说的，长大后，我们都会为那些
unique ones the weird ones and we steal
独特的人、那些特立独行的人鼓掌，我们会借鉴
from them and we aspire to be them and
他们，渴望成为他们，我们会向
we learn from them and you have in the
他们学习。在
very short amount of time that I've been
短短
speaking to you for like a week or
一周左右的时间里，你让我大
something have blown my mind open I got
开眼界，我
to see the behind the scenes of Beast
看到了Beast Games的幕后故事。
games and my entire mind as I sat there
我坐在沙发上，还记得当时看到幕后花絮时的情景，我的整个思维都炸开了。
just exploded MH and you made me um in
你让我
that moment realize how much I'd limited
意识到，
myself as someone that I considers
作为一个自认为很有抱负的人，我限制了自己多少。
limited myself and so I wanted to say
所以我想说声
thank you because you're not just doing
谢谢，因为你不仅
that for me you're doing that for tens
为我做了这些，你也为数
of millions hundreds of millions of
千万、数亿
people all at the same time and you're
人同时做了这些，你不仅为
giving them the the road map but also a
他们指明了方向，还……
blueprint and the mentality and the
蓝图、心态和
belief that they too don't have to live
信念，即他们也不必过着
the life that school or the system has
学校或社会中那种生活。 系统
told them they have in the Box agre
告诉他们，他们已经在盒子里了，
exactly so thank you so much honestly
完全同意，所以真的非常感谢你，
cuz we need more people like you and I'm
因为我们需要更多像你这样的人，我
I'm your biggest fan thank you I really
是你最大的粉丝，谢谢你，我真的非常非常
really appreciate you thank you all
感谢你，谢谢大家。
right let's see if we can break into a
好了，我们看看能不能闯进
Walmart you're so funny some of the most
沃尔玛。你真幽默。世界上一些最
successful fascinating and insightful
成功、最有魅力、最有洞察力的
people in the world have sat across from
人都曾坐在
me at this table and at the end of every
我对面的这张桌子旁，每次
conversation I asked them to leave a
谈话结束时，我都会请他们
question behind in the famous Diary of a
在著名的《CEO日记》上留下一个问题。这个
CEO and it's a question designed to
问题旨在
spark the kind of conversations that
引发最重要的对话，那种
that can change your life we then take
可以改变你人生的对话。然后，
those questions and we put them on these
我们将这些问题写在这些
cards on every single card you can see
卡片上。每张卡片上都可以看到提问者的名字和
question they asked and on the other
他们提出的问题。在
side if you scan that barcode you can
卡片的背面，如果你扫描条形码，就能
see who answered it next something I
看到谁回答了这个问题。接下来，我
know a lot of you have wanted to know
知道你们很多人都想知道，
and the only way to find out is by
而唯一的办法就是给
getting yourself some conversation cards
自己买一些对话卡片。
which you can play at home with friends
你可以在家和朋友家人玩，
and family at work with colleagues and
在工作中和同事玩，
also with total strangers on holiday
甚至在度假时和完全陌生的人玩。
I'll put a link to the conversation
我会把对话卡片的链接放在…… 详情请见
cards in the description below you can
下方描述，您可以
get yours at the diary.com
在 diary.com 获取。
[Music]
[音乐]
oh
哦